奇遇电影字幕组
QY-174
更多资讯请关注官方公众号：cinematik
翻译： @阿囤小兄弟  @一只醉丁  @不见老阿
翻译： @movie404  @鱼饲料1  @Tien_Sun
校对：@一个Delpy     @Florrie_likkke
时间轴：@Edandelion_   @一只醉丁   @33-eR
@-GOOEY     @没什么能难倒LeoQ
特效： @一只醉丁
[海边的曼彻斯特为美国马萨诸塞州的一座小城镇]
海边的曼彻斯特
世界上有很多东西是他不懂
...A lot of stuff that he just doesn't understand
但是我懂的
about the world that I understand
我就靠它来过日子呢
that makes... it makes all my actions when I move through the world...
我之所以能做得更好 是因为我能看到世界像地图一样
I do things better because i can see it all laid out
在我面前展开  你看过地图吗
like a map. Have you ever looked at a map?
- 看过      - 你知道怎么看地图吗
- Yes.        - Do you know how to read a map?
要是我没记错的话
if I'm not mistaken.
- 你知道怎么看地图吗      - 知道
- Do you know how to read a map?        - Yeah.
你爸爸是个大好人
Your father's a perfectly good guy,
可是这个世界上
but there's a lot of stuff
还有很多我知道
that he just doesn't understand about the world
- 而他不知道的事情      - 我爸爸
- that I understand.        - My dad--
- 等等 听着      - 我爸爸
- Wait. Listen.        - My daddy's--
我都还没问你问题呢
I haven't asked you a question yet.
我还没问你问题呢
I haven't asked you a question.
- 听着 嘘      - 我爸爸
- Listen. Shh.       - My daddy--
听着 别跟你爸说 闭嘴 安静
don't tell your father. Shut up! Be quiet.
嘘 安静 我还没问你问题呢
Shush. I haven't asked you the question yet.
我什么都还没问呢 听好了
I haven't asked you anything. Listen. Shh.
安静 没事 别担心
Quiet. We got it. Don't worry about it.
听着
Listen.
如果你可以带一个人跟你上岛
if you could take one guy to an island with you
你知道他会保护你 因为他是最厉害的人
and you knew you'd be safe because he was the best man
他会想办法活下去
and he was going to figure out how to survive,
他会做各种东西
he was going to make everything--
他会把这座岛变成一个美好的地方
make the world a good place on the island,
他会让你快乐
he was going to keep you happy,
他会…不管怎样 他都是这个差事的最佳人选
he-- this is the best man for the job, no matter what,
如果要你在我和你爸之间选
if it was between me and your father,
- 你会选谁      - 我爸爸
- who would you say?        - My daddy.
我不明白 等等
I don't see-- hang on a second.
等一下 听着
Hang on a second. Listen.
你肯定理解错这个问题了
I think you're wrong about that.
虽然是由你来选
It's your choice to make,
但是我想让你知道
but I want you to understand something:
有很多…
That there's a lot of--
嘿 捡起来… 什么情况 这是怎么回事
hey. Pick up-- what hap-- what is that?
不可以把鱼竿随便丢在这里
You can't leave your fishing rod like that.
我不知道它为什么一直滴水
I don't know why the hell it keeps dripping.
一晚上滴个不停
All night long-- drip, drip, drip.
这破玩意儿我都修了十回了
I've had the fucking thing repaired ten times.
你得换一个新的塞子
You need a new stopper.
那就行了?
Is that it?
你看塞子的边缘都烂成什么样了
Your stopper's--it's rotted all around the edges,
没办法密封
so it's not making a seal.
所以水滴到盆里了
The water's going to drip through to the bowl.
我可以
I could, uh--
我明天可以给你带个新的过来
I could bring you a new one tomorrow.
或者也许你可以考虑把整套装置换了
Or you might want to consider replacing the whole apparatus.
你觉得怎么办合适
What do you recommend?
嗯 我可以先把塞子换了
I could replace the stopper first.
如果不管用
If that doesn't work,
再来帮你更换整套家伙
I could replace the whole apparatus.
你就没点专业建议吗
You can't give me a professional recommendation?
反正随你
it's really up to you.
明天
Tomorrow
我嫂子和侄子们要来
my sister-in-law's coming over with the nephews.
我得去把车开回来
I got to take the car in.
不 是我妹妹珍妮的长女的成人礼
No, it's my sister jeanine's oldest daughter's bat mitzvah.
我等着到时候被无聊到死
I'm looking forward to being bored to death.
不是 那丫头不想办 她爸爸也不想办
the girl doesn't want it, her father doesn't want it,
我就更别提了
and don't even ask me.
七个小时的车程
Seven hours in the car.
我真的会想抹了自己的脖子
I could really slit my throat.
不过那几个小丫头还挺讨人喜欢的
But oh, well. The little girls are charming.
李 真不好意思
Lee, I'm so sorry.
没事
That's okay.
实在是很恶心
This is so gross.
没关系
That's all right.
不 让他来
No, tell him to come.
好的 嗯
Okay. Yeah.
不过辛迪 跟你说件事
But-- but-- but, Cindy, i have to tell you something.
我好像爱上我的修理工了
I'm, like, in love with my janitor.
会不会很变态
Is that sick?
你对你的修理工有没有过非分之想
Have you ever had a sexual fantasy about your handyman?
嗯 感觉很奇怪 因为他正在
Well, it's awkward because he's literally, like,
清理我马桶里塞住的屎
cleaning the shit out of my toilet bowl right now,
而且我觉得我现在这样真是没什么魅力可言
and I don't think I'm at my most alluring.
嗯 也许你说得对
Yeah, maybe you're right.
毕竟不是在社交场合碰到他…
It's not like i met him socially.
好的 谢谢你 辛迪
Okay, thank you, Cindy.
行 二十分钟吧 拜
Okay. Like 20 minutes. Bye.
你好 搞定了
Uh, hi. All set.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我能给你一点小费[小建议]吗
Can I give you a tip?
你是说你要提建议吗
You mean like a suggestion?
不 我是说 小费
No. I mean like a tip.
哦
Oh.
好 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
- 那好      - 好
- Okay.         - Okay.
晚安
Good night.
晚安 再见
Good night. Goodbye.
这该死的水管我得修多少遍才行
I mean, how many times do I have to fix these fucking pipes?
我每次一洗澡
Every time I take a shower,
公寓里就跟发大水一样
the entire apartment has a flood.
我真是被折腾疯了
It's driving me insane.
我明天带管道工过来
Well, I'll get you a plumber here tomorrow,
不过我们估计得把瓷砖敲开
but I'd say we're going to have to break through the tile
把漏水的部位隔离开来 因为下面已经积了很多水了
and isolate the leak because there's quite a lot of water down there.
可是你怎么知道是我家的问题 为什么问题就出在我家呢
How do you know it's me? Why is it automatically me?
因为如果是楼上的问题
Because if it was coming from higher up,
你的天花板或者墙上
you'd have water damage in your ceiling
会渗水的 但它们都是干的
or in your wall, and it's all dry.
好吧
Great.
可能只是缝隙漏水的问题
It might just be the caulking.
浴缸四周都要重新封一遍
This whole tub needs to be recaulked.
最近几个小时你是不是洗澡了
Have you taken a bath or a shower in the last couple of hours?
是啊
Yes.
那问题就在这了
It might just be that.
好吧 你打算怎么找漏水点
Okay. And how are you planning to find that out?
我们可以把淋浴打开
Well, we could run the shower
看水会不会滴到楼下
and see if it drips downstairs.
你是想让我现在洗个澡吗
Oh, you want me to take a shower right now?
不是
No.
你是想让我现在洗澡
You want me to take a shower right now
你在旁边站着
while you stand there watching to see
看水会不会漏到楼下弗雷德里克家吗
if it drips into the Fredrichs' apartment?
我他妈才不管你干什么 奥尔森太太
I don't give a fuck what you do, Mrs. Olsen.
我只想把这该死的漏水修好
I'm just trying to fix the fucking leak.
我不喜欢这样
I-- I didn't like that.
你居然敢这样跟我说话
How dare you talk to me like that.
你他妈给我滚出去
Get the fuck out of my fucking house.
好的
Okay.
趁我还没报警 滚出老娘家
Get the fuck out of my fucking house before I call the police.
好吧
All right.
你听不见吗 我说了滚出去
Did you hear me? I said get out.
我没法滚 你堵着门呢
I can't. You're blocking the doorway.
你他妈什么毛病啊
What the fuck's the matter with you?
你不能那样跟住户说话
You can't talk to the tenants like that.
听着 李 你活儿干得好
Look, Lee, you do good work.
人又可靠
You're dependable.
但是我老是收到投诉
But I get these complaints all the time.
说你没礼貌 不友好
You're rude, you're unfriendly.
连"早上好"也不说 拜托 别这样行吗
You won't say good morning. I mean, come on.
埃默里先生 我给他们修管道
Mr. Emery, i fix the plumbing,
帮他们扔垃圾 给他们刷墙
take out the garbage, paint their apartments.
还干电工的活儿
I do electrical work,
你我都知道这是违法的
which we both know is against the law.
我准时上班
I show up on time.
还要负责四栋楼
I'm working four buildings,
钱倒是都进了你的腰包
and you're getting all the money.
你想怎么样就怎么样吧
So do whatever you're gonna do.
你到底给不给奥尔森太太道歉
Would you be willing to apologize to Mrs. Olsen?
道什么歉
For what?
好吧 好吧 我去跟她谈谈
All right. All right. I'll talk to her.
- 嘿 李      - 谢谢
- Hey, Lee.        - Thanks.
- 你怎么样      - 挺好的
- How are you doing?        - Good.
最近还挺顺利的吧
How's things going, all right?
嗯
Yeah.
比赛看了吗
Watch the game?
看了
Yeah, I did.
你觉得他们有机会吗
You think they got a shot?
- 没有      - 你敢肯定?
- No.        - You bet?
我肯定
Yeah, I would.
他们输了前两场
They dropped the first two.
接下来三场照样会输
They're going to lose the next three.
- 给你      - 谢谢
- Here you go.        - Thanks.
天呐 对不起
Oh, my god. I'm so sorry.
没事
That's okay.
泼到你身上没
Did I get you?
是的
Yes.
- 泼到你身上了啊      - 没关系
- I got you. Uh...        - That's okay.
- 我给你拿点纸巾      - 我没事
- Let me get you some napkins.        - I'm okay.
嘿 莱尼 能不能给我点纸巾
Hey, Lenny, can i grab some napkins?
谢谢
Thanks.
Thank you.
给
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
没事
It's okay.
我泼了你一身啤酒
Well, now I spilled my beer all over you,
我叫莎伦
my name's Sharon.
嗯 不要紧
uh, it's okay.
你叫...
And you are?
李
Uh, Lee.
他过来了
Here he comes.
你好吗
How you doing?
- 你好啊      - 很好 我挺好的
- How you doing?        - Good. I'm good.
我想问一下 你们认识我吗
Hey, can I ask you guys, do you know me?
- 不认识      - 我也不认识
- Uh, I don't think so.        - Yeah, I don't think so either.
我们从来没见过？
We never met?
- 没见过      - 对 没见过
- No.        - No, not yet.
- 没见过      - 没有
- No, I don't think so.        - No.
那你们他妈的看我干什么
So what the fuck are you looking at me for?
- 什么      - 我说你他妈看我干什么
- Excuse me?        - I said what the fuck are you looking at me for?
- 你他妈给我滚蛋      - 先生 我们真的没看你…
- Hey, take a fuckin' walk.        - Sir, we weren't looking at you.
不不不 别跟这混蛋道歉
No, don't apologize to this asshole.
- 你他妈滚蛋      - 我们真的没在看你
- Take a fuckin' hike.        - We weren't looking at you, seriously.
拜托 哥们 喂
Come on, man! Hey!
放开我 我要滚蛋
Let me go! I gotta go take a hike!
我他妈要滚蛋
I wanna take a fuckin' hike!
喂 我是李
Hello, this is Lee.
哦 好的
Oh. Okay.
什么时候的事
When did that happen?
他现在怎么样了
Well, how's he doing now?
不 别告诉他
No, don't do that.
我现在就过来
I'm gonna come up there right now.
一个半小时内就到
I'll be up there in an hour and a half.
可以吗
Okay?
谢谢你
Thank you.
再见
Bye.
埃默里先生 还是我 我联系过何赛了
Mr. Emery, it's Lee again. I contacted Jose.
他至少能帮我代班到周五晚上
He can cover me till Friday night at least.
然后吉恩·麦克蒂维会负责到我回来
Uh, after that, Gene Macadavey will take over until I get back.
弗雷德里克家的天花板我就先不管了
Um, I wouldn't do anything with Mr.and Mrs. Fredrich's ceiling
等你找到专业的管道工再说吧
until you you get a real plumber in there.
那你准备怎么办呢
But what are you gonna do?
有什么消息我会第一时间跟你说
I will, uh, let you know as soon as I have more information.
我至少要在曼彻斯特待一周
I should be in Manchester a week at least.
非常感谢 再见
Thank you very much. Bye.
快点
Come on!
走啊
Go!
- 嘿 李      - 他去世了吗
- Hey, Lee.        - Is he dead?
节哀顺变 李
I'm sorry, Lee.
他一个小时前过世了
He passed away about an hour ago.
- 噢      - 节哀顺变
- Oh.        - I'm so sorry.
- 你见到他了吗      - 没有
- Did you see him?        - No.
- 我是说 我送他来医院的      - 乔治送他来医院的
- I mean, I brought him in.        - George brought him in.
我们早上正在检查船只
We were looking at the boat this morning,
他就...
and he just--
我也搞不清 就像是摔倒了
I don't know, he just, like, fell over.
一开始我以为他在开玩笑
I thought he was kidding me at first.
然后我叫了救护车
Then I called the ambulance, and, uh...
然后 就这样了
That was it.
我去叫穆勒医生 告诉他你来了
I'll just call Dr. Muller and tell him that you're here.
贝特尼医生去哪了
Where's Dr. Betheny?
她在休产假 哦 他来了
Oh, she's on maternity leave. Here he is.
李 我是穆勒医生 我们通过电话
Lee, I'm Dr. muller. We spoke on the phone.
- 嗯 嗨      - 我非常非常遗憾
- Yeah, hi.        - I'm very, very sorry.
- 谢谢      - 你好 乔治
- Thank you.        - Hello, George.
- 嘿 吉姆      - 你还好吧
- Hiya, Jim.        - How you holding up?
还行吧 你也知道
Oh, great, you know
- 嗯 真是难过的一天      - 是啊
- It's a very sad day.        - Yeah.
我哥在哪
Where's my brother?
他在楼下 愿意的话 你可以去看他
Oh, he's downstairs. You can see him if you want.
他怎么了
What happened to him?
心脏骤停
Just a cardiac arrest.
他的心脏十分脆弱
You know his heart's very weak at this point.
然后就停止跳动了
It just gave out.
我很遗憾你没能及时赶到
I'm really sorry you couldn't get here in time,
但是我在电话里跟你说到…
but as I told you before--
操他妈的
aw, fuck this.
对不起
Sorry.
- 没关系      - 真没事 哥们
- That's okay, buddy.        - That's perfectly all right.
有人通知我叔叔吗
Did anybody call my uncle?
就是唐尼叔叔
It's their uncle Donny.
嗯 我叔叔婶婶
Yeah, my aunt and uncle.
- 应该有人通知他们       - 没有 李 没通知
- Somebody should have called--        - no, Lee. Lee, no.
- 怎么了      - 唐尼在明尼苏达州找了个活
- What? What?        - Donny got a job in Minnesota.
- 有一阵儿了      - 明尼苏达?
- Like, a while ago.        - Minnesota?
嗯 他在明尼苏达的明尼通卡
Yeah, he got a job in some outfit
找到了工作
in minnetonka, Minnesota,
信不信由你
if you can believe that.
- 乔没跟你说吗      - 没有
- Joe didn't tell you about that?        - No.
如果你需要的话 我可以打给他 李
I can call him if you want, Lee,
告诉他们这件事
and tell him what happened.
- 行 谢谢      - 哦 不用谢
- Okay, thanks.        - No problem.
跟他说一下这件事情
Tell him what happened.
跟他说我今晚会给他打电话
Tell him I'll call him tonight.
商量后事
Talk about arrangements.
谁通知一下我妻子
Somebody should call my wife.
- 你的…      - 前妻
- Your, uh, uh...        - Ex-wife.
- 你是说兰迪      - 兰迪
- You mean Randi?        - Randi.
- 对 抱歉 我是说兰迪      - 没关系
- Yes, I'm sorry. I meant Randi.        - That's okay.
我明白你的意思 交给我吧
I already thought of that. I'll take care of it.
- 行 谢谢      - 别客气
- Okay. Thank you.        - No problem.
- 我能去看他了吗      - 当然
- Can I see him now?        - Sure.
李 我可以在这里等你
Lee, I can wait up here.
要是需要我帮忙的话
Lee, if you need anything.
好
Okay.
- 谢谢      - 嗯
- Thanks.        - Yeah.
需要纸巾吗
Would you like a kleenex?
- 好的 谢谢      - 好
- Yeah, thanks. Yeah.        - Yeah.
麻烦给我点纸巾
Can I get a couple kleenex, please?
谢谢 亲爱的
Thanks, hon.
- 对不起       - 没事
- I'm sorry.        - Oh, please.
- 贝特尼医生怎么样了      - 她挺好的
- How is Dr. betheny?        - Oh, she's doing very well.
刚生了一对双胞胎女儿
She just had twin girls.
- 艾琳跟我说了      - 对啊
- Oh, Irene told me that.        - Yeah.
我下午就打电话告诉她这事
I call this afternoon and tell her what happened.
她以前对他很好
She was very good to him.
是啊
Yeah, she was.
这种病通常被称为充血性心力衰竭
The disease is commonly referred to as congestive heart failure.
- 我的天呐      - 你很熟悉这个病吗
- Oh, my god.        - Are you familiar with it?
- 不熟      - 那你"我的天"个什么啊
- No.      - Then what are you saying "oh, my god" for?
- 因为...这是什么病啊      - 她正跟咱们解释呢 亲爱的
- Because-- what is it?        - She's trying to explain it, honey.
- 抱歉 贝…      - 贝特尼
- I'm sorry, Dr. Beth--        - Betheny.
- 贝特尼 抱歉 我老是记不住      - 没事
- Betheny, I'm sorry. I can never get it right.       - Not a problem.
所以 你刚才说
So you were saying.
它是心脏肌肉的逐渐退化
It's a gradual deterioration of the muscles of the heart.
通常发生在老年人身上
It's usually associated with older people.
但在极少数的情况下 也会发生在年轻人身上
But in rare cases, it will occur in a younger person.
有的人能活五十到六十年 只是偶尔发作一下
Some people live up to 50-60 years with just an occasional attack.
但是绝大多数患者都是周期性发作
But most people suffer periodic episodes,
就像你周一那次
like the one you had on Monday,
出现的类似于心脏病发作的症状
which mimic the symptoms of a heart attack,
它还会进一步削弱肌肉力量
and which further weaken the muscle.
让你一整周 或是两周都无法正常工作
They can put you out of commission for a week, two weeks.
你需要住院观察 这样我们就可以监控你的心脏
And you'll need to be hospitalized so we can monitor your heart,
因为心脏停搏的风险在这一两周内较高
because the risk of cardiac arrest is elevated for a week or two.
- 我的天呐      - 没事
- Oh, my god.        - It's okay.
但在两次发作的间隙 绝大多数患者跟健康人没两样
But in between, most people feel perfectly healthy
基本上可以正常生活
you can basically live a normal life.
等等 你说有些人活了五六十年是什么意思
Wait. So what do you mean some people live to be 50-60 years?
你是说一共活了这么多年
I mean, are you saying total?
还是确诊后又活了五六十年
Or are saying when they're diagnosed with this?
还是什么 你是什么意思
Or what? What are you saying?
跟我说实话
And tell me the fuckin' truth.
一共
Total.
对于和您症状相近的病人来说
For most people with the particulars of your condition,
平均寿命一般为再活五到十年
the average life expectancy is five to ten years.
但是数据变动区间很大 你不是数据
The statistics vary widely. You're not a statistic.
而是活生生的人
You're just one person,
我们尚不清楚你的状况会怎样
and we don't know what's gonna happen to you yet.
但是这个病情况并不乐观
But it's not a good disease.
有什么病是乐观的吗
What is a good disease?
- 被毒藤刺了起皮疹      - 香港脚
- Poison Ivy.        - Athlete's foot?
- 这是个喜剧梗      - 埃莉斯 别闹了
- It's a comedy routine.        - Elise, please.
- 老天啊      - 我的天呐
- For Christ's sake.        - Oh, my god!
我做什么都是错的
When am I gonna put one foot right?
- 能不能告诉我要怎么办      - 埃莉斯
- How about a hint?        - Elise...
- 爸爸      - 怎么了
- Daddy.        - What?
她没事
She's fine.
我们都很难过
We're all upset.
咱们都好好听
We're all gonna listen,
然后想知道什么就问什么
then we're gonna ask any of the questions we wanna ask,
再一起想解决办法 好吗
and then we're gonna figure out what to do together, right?
- 好      - 当然
- Right.        - Sure.
所以 贝丝医生 你刚才说
So you were saying, Dr. Beth.
- 是贝特尼医生 爸      - 贝特尼医生 爸 你记清楚好吗
- Betheny, dad.        - It's Dr. Betheny, dad. Get it right.
我看不出来在这种情形下有什么好笑的
I do not see where the humor lies in this situation.
- 埃莉斯 你要冷静      - 不要
- Elise, you must calm down.        - No.
- 对不起 我不是真的要…      - 没事没事 不用道歉
- I'm sorry, I'm not trying to--        - no, no, don't.
不 行了 我不…
more. I'm not gonna. Nope.
- 埃莉斯 我给你倒杯水吧      - 不用了
- Elise, let me get you a glass of water.        - No.
- 爸 算了      - 对 算了 就像你一样
- Daddy, forget it.        - Forget it like you.
大家都应该像你这样
Everybody should be just like you.
你猜怎么着 我受够了在这唱黑脸
You know what? I am tired of being the bad guy here.
天呐 到底是谁住院啊
Jesus Christ! Who's in the fuckin' hospital here?
没错 所以我来唱黑脸
Right. Right. So I'll be the bad guy,
你住你的院 自己跟你儿子解释这出笑话吧
and you be in the hospital and explain the jokes to your son.
- 我回家了      - 你要回家?
- I'm going home.        - You're going home?
- 你真回家啊      - 没错
- You're going home?        - Yep!
- 我去叫她回来      - 去她的
- Let me get her back.        - Fuck her.
- 你就会干这种事      - 你能不能少说两句
- Come on with that stuff already!        - Stop that shit!
谢谢你 托尼
Thank you, Tony.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我得去趟曼彻斯特
I have to get up to Manchester.
还没有人告诉帕特里克 对吧
Nobody told Patrick, right?
没有 你让我们等你过来再说
No, you had asked for us to wait for you to get here.
- 是的 谢谢      - 好
- Yes. Thank you.        - Okay.
那么 接下来该怎么做
So, um, what is the procedure now?
现在你要联系一家殡仪馆来安排后面的事情
Oh, now you have to make arrangements with a funeral parlor.
他们基本上会把所有的事情都安排好的
And they pretty much take care of everything.
我连一家殡仪馆都不知道
I don't know the name of one.
没关系 我们可以帮你
That's all right. We can help you with that.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
他们会直接过来把他接走?
And they'll just come and pick him up?
- 是的      - 是
- Yeah.        - Yes.
- 我可以帮忙打电话 李      - 好
- I can make those calls, Lee.        - Okay.
如果你需要任何帮助的话 尽管说
Let me know if you need any help with anything.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thank you. Hmm.
是啊 我们还得谈谈那条船
Yeah, we've gotta talk about the boat
还有网站
and the website,
等等东西
and all that.
没问题 随时找我
Sure. I'm around.
我得在学校放学之前赶到那里 所以...
I gotta get up there before school let's out, so--
你只要签字确认乔的遗物就行了
you just have to sign for Joe's belongings.
这边
Right this way.
在这边签字
Just gotta sign right here.
乔的遗物在哪里 就是放在这里的那个塑料袋
Where's Joe's belongings? The plastic bag right here.
不好意思 稍等一下
Sorry. Give me a sec.
乔的遗物放在哪了
Where's Joe's belongings?
好 好 这很棒
All right, all right. That's good. Hup!
- 像这样?      - 没错 不过别把你的大拇指放在鱼线上
- Like that?        - Yeah, but keep your thumb off the line,
因为如果有鱼上钩 鱼线就会直接把手指割破
because, if you get a strike, it's gonna slice it right open,
接下去会发生什么你知道吗
and you know what happens then?
- 什么      - 鲨鱼会闻到血腥味
- What?        - The sharks will smell the blood,
然后把这条船撕成两半
and they'll rip this boat apart.
- 才不会呢      - 会的
- No, they won't.        - Yeah, they will.
爸爸 鲨鱼会这样吗
Dad, will they?
- 是的 先生      - 闭嘴
- Yes, sir.        - Shut up.
我见过一群鲨鱼像撕硬纸板一样
You know, I've seen a school of sharks tear a boat to pieces
把船撕成碎片
like it was made of cardboard,
就因为有个小孩把创口贴扔进海里了
because some kid threw a band-aid in the water.
对啊
Oh, yeah.
真的
Yeah, he did.
- 是啊      - 你才没见过
- Oh, yeah.        - No, you didn't.
有时候避开它们的唯一方法
Sometimes the only way to keep them off is to throw the kid
就是直接把小孩扔进海里来分散它们的注意力
directly in the ocean to distract them.
你闭嘴 鲨鱼才不是成群结队游来游去的
Shut up. Sharks don't even swim in schools.
他说鲨鱼不是成群结队游的
He says sharks don't swim in schools.
- 真是聪明的孩子      - 可不是嘛
- Smart kid.        - Yeah, he is.
聪明的孩子正是一大群鲨鱼
A really smart kid is exactly the kind of quality meal
围着船想找的美味晚餐
a humongous school of sharks is looking for when they're circling a boat.
李叔叔 你闭嘴
Oh, uncle Lee, shut up.
有鱼上钩了 上钩了 上钩了
Hey, you got a strike! Strike, strike, strike!
慢慢拉 慢慢拉 小心你的大拇指
Ease up on the drag, and watch your fuckin' thumb!
- 你有鱼上钩啦      - 别打我
- You got a strike now!        - Jesus! Don't hit me!
- 闭嘴啦 不许说脏话      - 他钓到鱼啦
- No swearing!        - He got a strike!
- 慢慢来      - 我能搞定 我们能搞定
- Ease up on it.        - I got it! We got it!
专心开船 你忙你的去
Drive the boat! Mind your business!
- 你们要赶紧把鱼钩住      - 这是什么鱼
- You gotta get the hook in him.        - What kind of fish is it?
我们没事 闭嘴 你忙你的去
We're fine! Shut up! Mind your business!
- 这是什么鱼      - 巨大的白色的
- What kind of fish is it?        - Great white.
- 一定是条大白鱼      - 闭嘴
- It's gotta be a great white.        - Shut up!
或许是条梭子鱼 谁知道呢
Or maybe a barracuda. Who knows?
这才不是鲨鱼
It's not a shark!
- 加油 把它拉上来      - 才不是鲨鱼呢
- Come on, pull him up!        - It's not a shark!
- 我们先别说话了...      - 快点
- Just stop talking!        - Come on!
那个怎么会跟那些是连在一起的
How come that's connected to those?
没有连在一起 只是看起来这样而已
It's not connected, it just looks that way.
我来教你认认这些岛屿
I'm trying to teach you the islands.
这是那个有钱人买的岛
That's the island the rich guy bought
所以其他人都不能在上面安家了
so no one else would put a house on it.
他就是这么有钱
That's how rich he is.
贝克岛 密瑟里岛
Baker island, Misery island.
我和你兰迪阿姨就是在密瑟里岛结婚的
Misery island's where me and your aunt Randi got married.
- 哈喽      - 嗨
- Hello?        - Yeah, hi.
苏西 爸爸回来了
Suzy, daddy's home.
嗨 苏西 爸爸回来了
Hi, Suzy. Daddy's home.
- 嗨 爸比      - 嗨 亲爱的
- Hi, daddy.        - Hi, sweetheart.
要抱抱
Hug.
天哪 你要把我的脖子弄断啦
Oh, Jesus Christ! You're breaking my neck!
李?
Lee?
来啦
Yeah, hang on.
- 嗨 玩得开心吗      - 太开心了
- Hey. Did you have a good time?        - Yeah, really good.
- 你妈妈呢      - 他们刚走
- Where's your mother?        - They just left.
不是吧
Oh, no!
是啊 没看到你 她也很难过
Yeah, she's sad to miss you too.
总有下一次的 你睡了吗
Well, there's always next time. Did you get any sleep?
是啊 我妈妈在的时候她倒是挺安静的
Oh, yeah, it's so restful when my mother's here.
真遗憾 嗨 小凯
Oh, too bad. Hi, Kary.
- 嗨 爸比      - 来
- Hi, daddy.        - Come here.
- 放我下来      - 我会把你放下来的 放轻松
- Put me down.        - I'm putting you down. Relax.
我只是想亲亲你 宝贝 好了
I'm just giving you a kiss. Honey, all right--
凯伦 凯伦
Karen! Karen!
- 我差点就要摔到你的头了      - 天哪
- I almost dropped you on your head.        - Jesus.
我开了一家美发店
I'm making a hair salon.
那很棒哦
Oh, yeah? It's really good.
你想给我剪头发吗
You wanna cut my hair?
只对女生开放 不好意思
It's just for girls. I'm sorry.
好吧 我理解 宝贝
That's all right. I understand, sweetheart.
我能看电视找找灵感吗
Can I watch TV to get some ideas?
- 不行     - 好呀
- No.         - Yeah.
去吧
Go ahead.
走开
Get off.
噢 天呐
Oh, god.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
好点了
Better.
- 是吗      - 是啊
- Yeah?        - Yeah.
听起来是好点了
You sound better.
所以你们真的会用渔具吗
So did you guys actually use the fishing tackle?
是啊 那当然了
Oh, yeah.
小帕抓住一条巨大的蓝鱼 十八磅
Patty caught a humongous bluefish-- 18 pounds.
是吗 那真是太厉害了
Oh, yeah? Well, that's awesome.
我从来没见谁这么开心过
Oh, I never seen anybody so happy in my whole life.
这里真整洁呢
Oh, its nice in here.
你把这里整理得干干净净 哇
You keep it nice. Wow.
- 真是持家能手啊      - 滚开
- What a homemaker.        - Fuck off.
好了 走开
All right. Get away from me.
别这样
Stop it.
别 别这样
Oh, don't. Stop.
拜托 我生病了
Please, I'm sick.
好了 走开
Okay. For real, get off of me.
- 嗨 斯坦尼      - 哦 天呐 别去吵他
- Hi, Stanny.        - Oh, god, let him alone.
- 你怎么不哭了呢      - 我才刚把他哄睡着
- How come you're not crying?        - I just got him settled.
- 你干嘛要把他哄睡着呢      - 李 别把他抱起来
- What did you get him settled for?        - Lee, don't pick him up.
如果他没在哭 就见好就收吧
If he's not crying, leave well enough alone.
我和你妈妈当初就应该"见好就收"
Leave well enough alone. That's what me and your mommy
而不是结婚
should have done instead of getting married.
噢 闭嘴吧
Oh, shut up.
那么世界上就不会有你了 也不会有你姐姐们了
Then you wouldn't be here. Your sisters wouldn't be here,
我就可以在自己的客厅安安静静地看球了
and I could watch the football game in my own living room with peace and quiet.
去死吧你
You know what? You can go fuck yourself.
噢 你好啊 小朋友
Oh, jeez Louise. Hey, kiddo.
天哪 你长得真帅 你知道吗
Oh, my gosh. You're very handsome, you know that?
看到没 我可没把他弄哭
See that? I didn't make him cry.
抱起来 放回去
Up and down.
好的
Yeah.
他没哭哦
He's not crying...
因为我知道怎么搞定他
'Cause I know how to handle him.
乔呢 他怎么样
How is he? How's Joe?
挺好的 他还行吧
He's fine. You know, he's-- he's all right.
他还挺好的
Actually, he's doing all right.
你们的啤酒还够喝吗 你们这一天过得还好吗
And you didn't run out of beer? You got through the day okay?
对啊 我们都很克制的
Oh, yeah. We were very temperate.
我不知道你们为什么总要跑到那条该死的船上去
I don't know why you guys bother getting on the friggin' boat.
这是什么意思 因为我们喜欢大海
What do you mean? We love the sea.
是吗 你在海上喝了多少啤酒
Oh, yeah? How many beers did you have on the sea?
- 八瓶      - 八瓶?
- Eight.         - Eight?
是啊 七个小时
Yep, eight,
喝了八瓶 那...
over a seven-hour period, which--
哇 你可真行
wow, I am well impressed.
就是...
...is...
一小时1.1428572瓶啤酒
...1.1428572 beers an hour.
你难道没有什么别的能喝了吗
It's like you didn't even have anything to drink at all.
我跟你说了 我已经在减量了
Yeah, I told you i was cutting down.
哦 天呐 不要 你想干什么
Oh, god, no. What do you think you're gonna do?
我想我应该洗个澡
I guess I'm gonna take a shower.
兰迪 我发誓
Randi, I swear to god.
你应该看看他的表情
You should have seen his face.
太开心了
So happy.
就像我们带女儿去坐旋转木马一样
It was like when we took the girls on the merry-go-round.
那是纯粹的开心
I mean, it was just pure happiness.
拜托 我病了
Oh, come on, I'm sick.
我病了 我真的
I'm sick. I'm really,
真的 不太舒服
really, deeply sick.
我快要不能呼吸了
It actually makes it hard to breathe.
他不在学校? 我以为学校放学...
He's not at school? I thought school left out--
- 我敢肯定他会...      - 什么
- I'm pretty sure he would have--         - what?
抱歉 保罗 我的手机
I'm sorry, Paul, my phone is--
- 不好意思 能再说一遍吗      - 没事
- sorry. Say that again?         - That's all right.
我敢肯定他现在应该去参加冰球训练了
I'm pretty sure he would have left for hockey practice by now.
他是冰球队的?
He's on the hockey team?
是啊 而且他也打得很好
Yeah. Yeah, he's doing real well too.
乔怎么样 他没事吧
Hey, how's Joe doing? He gonna be okay?
他没事
Yeah, he's fine.
训练在哪里 在学校吗
Where's the practice? Is it at the school?
不是的 他们在附近的格洛斯特训练
No, they practice at Gloucester around.
- 他们在...      - 不好意思
- They practice in the--       - I'm sorry.
- 不在学校吗      - 不在
- It's not at the school?        - No.
- 什么 抱歉      - 是的
- What? I'm sorry.        - Yeah.
- 能听见吗      - 手机...
- Can you hear me?         - The phone is--
没事 能听见我说话吗
that's all right. Can you hear me?
- 听得见      - 在格洛斯特 好吗
- Yes.         - It's at Gloucester, okay?
好 我知道了
Okay. I understand.
我们要打罗克波特队 不过他们暂时领先
We play with the Rockport team, but they're the lead team.
好的 我知道了 谢谢你 保罗
Okay, I understand. Thank you, Paul.
好的 没事 替我问候乔 好吗
Yeah, sure thing. Give Joe my regards, all right?
- 我会的      - 怎么了
- I will.        - What's up?
乔·钱德勒又进医院了
Uh, Joe Chandler's in the hospital again.
- 真可怕      - 是啊
- Oh, how awful.        - Yeah.
- 电话里的是谁      - 是李·钱德勒
- Who was on the phone?        - That was Lee Chandler.
- 李·钱德勒?      - 就是那个
- Lee Chandler?        - The very one.
嘿
Hey!
停下来
Knock it off!
钱德勒 给我住手
Chandler! Knock it off!
再有一次你就下场
One more time and you're out.
听懂了吗 钱德勒 再有一次
You understand that, Chandler? One more time.
- 我操      - 你说什么
- Ah, fuck me.        - What's that?
- 操你妈的      - 好了 你出局了
- Fuck my fuckin' ass.        - All right, you're out.
- 钱德勒 去替补席待着      - 好吧
- Chandler, you're benched.        - All right.
好像我在乎似的
Ask me if I give a shit.
你说什么
What was that?
教练 那是他叔叔
Coach, that's his uncle.
他爸爸肯定又进医院了
His father must be in the hospital.
- 谁的爸爸 钱德勒爸爸吗      - 他只会在...
Whose father, chandlers?        - Yeah, he only comes around--
他有心力衰竭
he's got congestive heart failure.
我是说帕特里克的爸爸 不是帕特里克
Patrick's dad, I mean, not-- not Patrick.
所以那是李·钱德勒 就是那个李·钱德勒?
So that's Lee Chandler.  The Lee Chandler, huh?
是啊 不过教练你知道那个故事是扯淡吧
Yeah, but coach, you know that story's bullshit, right?
完全是瞎扯 教练
Total bullshit, coach.
注意你们的用词
You guys wanna watch the language?
- 对不起      - 对不起
- Sorry.        - Sorry.
好了 管好你们自己的事 好吗
All right. Mind your own business for a little while, huh?
休息一下 喝点水
Let's take a break. Get a water.
所以 你爸爸怎么样了
So, uh, something going on with your dad?
他爸爸今天早上去世了
His father passed away this morning.
哦 天呐
Oh, jeez.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry to hear that. I really am.
我...听着 有事的话你尽管去
I, uh-- well, listen, do what you gotta do.
我真的觉得很难过
I, uh-- I feel terrible.
要不你去
Why don't you, uh--
你去把衣服换下来
all right, well, go in and change,
我们一会儿再说 好吗
and we'll talk about it later, all right?
去吧 我在外面等你
Go ahead. I'll meet you outside.
- 好      - 好 谢谢
- All right.        - All right. Thank you.
好了 别看戏了
All right, show's over.
快过来 开始了
Come on, let's go.
- 你还好吗      - 我的...
- You all right?        - Uh, my--
把你的球棍收起来 好吗
take your sticks back, would you?
- 回头见      - 好的
- Hey, I'll see you in there.        - Yeah.
- 我们一会儿再说吧      - 我过会儿打给你
- We'll talk, okay?        - I'll talk to you soon.
一会儿见 爱你
See you soon. I love you.
整队
Line it up again.
快来 开始了
Come on, let's go.
我要回医院去签一些文件
I have to go to the hospital and sign some more papers.
你想看看他吗
Do you wanna see him?
我不知道 为什么
I don't know. Why?
他看起来什么样
What's he look like?
他看起来就像死了一样
He looks like he's dead.
我是说 他看起来不像是睡着了之类的
I mean, he doesn't look like he's sleeping or anything.
看起来也不恶心
But he doesn't look gross, either.
我不知道
I don't know.
你也不是一定要去
Well, you know, you don't have to.
我想见见他
I wanted to see him.
但你可能不想在记忆里留下那样的画面
Maybe you don't want that image in your memory.
我不...
I don't--
你自己决定
it's up to you.
你现在准备怎么样
What do you wanna do?
想让我带你回家吗
You want me to take you home?
想让我帮你决定吗
Want me to decide for you?
我们走吧
Let's just go.
你他妈在干嘛
What the fuck are you doing?
- 我说我们进去吧      - 不 你说的是"我们走吧"
- I just said let's go inside!        - No, you said let's just go,
- 然后你就下车了      - 我的意思是我们进去吧
- and then you get out of the car?        - I meant let's go inside.
- 你他妈怎么回事      - 你有什么问题
- What the matter with you?        - What's your problem?
- 我的问题就是我差点扯断你他妈的腿      - 好好
- My problem is I could have ripped your fuckin' leg off!        - Okay, okay!
对不起 是我用错了英语单词
I'm sorry I misused the English language.
对不起 李叔叔
I'm sorry, uncle Lee.
我也跟你道歉 我只是吓到了
I'm sorry, too. I just get scared.
好了 可以了 谢谢
Yeah, okay, thank you.
没事
Of course.
你要按遥控门才开
You gotta hit the bleeper.
我没有遥控
I don't have a bleeper.
我去开吧 要输密码
I'll do it. There's a code.
我可以叫几个朋友过来吗
Hey, is it okay if I invite some of my friends over?
- 我跟他们说了 我会打给他们      - 好的
- I told them I would call them.        - Go ahead.
我们可以叫点披萨吗 因为这里没有什么吃的
And can we get some pizza? 'Cause there's nothing to eat here.
好
Okay.
- 你喜欢什么样的      - 什么样的都行
- What kind would you like?        - Any kind is fine.
谢谢
Thank you.
至少他没有受病痛折磨
At least he didn't suffer.
这对家人来说更难过 但是对本人来说是好事
It's worse for the family, but it's better for the person.
他真的是一个很好的人 帕特里克
Well, he was a fuckin' great guy, Patrick, I'll tell you that.
毋庸置疑
That's for sure.
我还记得有一次他
Yeah, I remember this one time he--
他开船带我们出海 大概六年级的时候
he took us out in the boat, like, in sixth grade.
是啊 我记得
Yeah, I remember that.
他让我们穿上救生衣
He made us wear these life preservers.
然后我说
And I was like, you know,
"有什么区别呢 钱德勒先生"
"what's the difference, Mr. Chandler?
"在这样的天气下 如果船沉了 我们怎么都会死的"
The boat sinks in this weather, we're dead anyways."
- 是啊 我记得      - 然后他说
- Yeah, I remember that.        - Then he goes,
"救生衣的作用是 当你掉进水里之后 鲨鱼更容易看到你"
"the life jacket's to make it easy on the sharks once you go over."
真是个聪明的家伙
Fuckin' smart ass, i swear to god.
是啊 他真的很喜欢拿鲨鱼开玩笑
Yeah, he really liked those shark jokes.
- 有趣的人      - 他真有趣 哥们
- Funny guy.        - He was funny, man.
没错 他也很温柔
Yeah, he was gentle too, you know?
跟他的儿子一样
Like his son.
然后这个前星际飞船舰长
So there's this former starship captain, all right?
什么 又聊星际迷航?
Jesus Christ! With the Star Trek again?
- 你他妈闭嘴      - 去你妈的 星际迷航烂透了
- Will you shut the fuck up?        - Fuck you. Star Trek sucks.
你这个该死的白痴
You fuckin' retard.
星际迷航是当代娱乐的经典核心
Star Trek's one of the classical pillars of modern entertainment.
- 是吗      - 好吗
- Oh yeah?        - All right?
那你来说说星际迷航 让我好好听听
Tell me about Star Trek. Enlighten me, motherfucker.
- 我告诉你      - 我跟你做朋友多久了
- I'll tell you this--        - how long have I been friends with you?
- 你还好吗 亲爱的      - 我没事
- How you doing, baby?        - I'm okay.
好了 够了 好吗 不就是星际迷航嘛
Enough is enough, okay? It's just Star Trek.
- 你好大的胆子 给我闭嘴      - 该死的星际迷航
- How dare you! Will you shut up?        - Fuck Star Trek.
所有你喜欢的经典科幻电影都是以星际迷航为基础的
Every Sci-Fi classic film you like was based on Star Trek.
星际迷航就是扯淡
Star Trek's bullshit.
- 对吧 星际迷航...      - 星际迷航蠢极了
- Right? Start trek--  - Star Trek's retarded.
- 然后是公路勇士      - 蠢
- Then the road warrior.         - Retarded.
- 还有黑客帝国      - 又蠢又烂
- Then the matrix.         - Retarded and shit.
我超爱星际迷航
I love Star Trek!
- 哦 是吗      - 你怎么敢这么说
- Oh, yeah, do you?        - How dare you?
你问帕特里克 他也喜欢 他也喜欢
Ask Patrick. He loves 'em! He loves 'em!
- 好吧 帕特里克 你觉得呢      - 来 问帕特里克
- All right. Patrick, what do you think?        - Go ahead, ask Patrick.
不敢相信我们现在在讨论星际迷航
I can't believe we're talking about Star Trek right now.
- 我喜欢星际迷航      - 谢谢你
- I like Star Trek.         - Thank you.
李叔叔
Hey, uncle Lee.
希尔薇可以在这里过夜吗
Is it okay if Silvie sleeps over?
爸爸都同意让她过夜的
Dad always let her.
那你为什么要问我呢
Then what are you asking me for?
不为什么
No reason.
谢谢
Thanks.
以防万一 我还是说一下
Uh, not that it would come up or anything,
她父母以为她在这过夜的时候是睡在楼下房间的
but her parents thinks she stays downstairs when she stays over.
所以万一他们问起的话
So if it comes up for some reason,
你能告诉他们 她是睡在楼下的房间吗
can you just say she stayed in the downstairs room?
- 我都不认识他们      - 你认识的
- I don't even know them.        - Yeah, you do.
米根夫妇 弗兰克和帕特
It's the Mcganns. It's Frank and Pat Mcgann.
- 她是希尔薇·米根?      - 是的
- Oh, that's Silvie Mcgann?        - Yeah.
- 好吧      - 所以
- Okay.        - So...
你可以说她是睡楼下的吗
Do you mind saying she stayed downstairs,
如果他们打电话过来之类的
like, if they call or something?
好
Okay.
我应该告诉你要用安全套吗
Am I supposed to tell you to use a condom?
不用 我是说
No. I mean--
- 乔会这么说吗      - 不会
- is that what Joe would say?        - No.
我是说 没错 我们讨论过这个话题
Well, I mean, yeah, we've had the discussion and everything.
- 所以...      - 那好
- So...       - Yeah, good.
是啊 如果我们太吵的话告诉我
Yeah, just let me know if we're making too much noise.
好
Okay.
你觉得我应该打给妈妈吗
Um, do you think i should call my mom
告诉她爸爸的事
to tell her about dad?
- 不 是我我就不会 小帕      - 好吧
- No, I wouldn't, Patty.        - Yeah.
我是说 都没人知道她在哪里
I mean, uh, nobody even knows where she is.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊 我知道 我只是好奇你会怎么想
Yeah, no, I was just curious what you thought.
不管怎么样... 晚安 李叔叔
Anyway, good night, uncle Lee.
晚安
Good night.
所以你要因为漏了个球生一晚上的气吗
Are you gonna sulk all night long because you dropped the goddamn ball?
- 我没有生气      - 闭嘴
- I'm not sulking.        - Oh, shut up.
如果你戴了该死的棒球手套的话 那个球也就不会掉了
If you'd use a goddamn baseball mitt, you wouldn't drop the fuckin' ball.
我不用手套 我不戴手套接得更好
I don't need a baseball mitt! I catch better without one.
闭嘴 闭嘴 埃莉斯
Hey, shut up. Hey, Elise!
该死 嘿
Oh, shit. Hey.
过来 李 你带小帕上楼
Come on. Hey, Lee, you wanna take Patty upstairs
给他洗个澡好吗
and get him washed up?
- 过来 孩子      - 去吧
- Come on, kid.        - Go on, now.
没事的 我一会儿就上去
It'll be all right. I'll be up in a minute.
上楼吧 小帕 没事的
Go on upstairs, Patty. Everything will be okay.
我觉得你失误的那个球也挺好的
I thought it was wonderful how you dropped that ball.
- 好吧      - 我没想让你接到
- Okay.        - I didn't want you to catch it.
该死
Oh, shit.
走开
Go on.
操
Fuck's sake.
快他妈闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
亲爱的妈妈
我写信是想告诉你
麻烦接 马萨诸塞州贝弗利的加拉格尔殡仪馆
Beverly, Massachusetts, Gallagher funeral home, please.
早上好
Morning.
嗨
Hi.
是的 你好 我叫李·钱德勒
Yes, hi, my name is Lee Chandler.
我的哥哥乔瑟夫·钱德勒现在在贝弗利医院的太平间
My brother, Joseph Chandler, is at the Beverly Hospital morgue.
我在想
I'm wondering, uh,
商量后面的安排要找谁呢
who I need to talk to about making arrangements?
好的 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
是的
Yes.
是的 我刚刚跟...
Yes, I just spoke--
是的 我叫李·钱德勒
yes, my name is Lee Chandler.
我的哥哥正在贝弗利医院的太平间
My brother is at the Beverly hospital morgue.
是的
Yes.
好
Okay.
我明白 我...
I understand, I'm--
我打电话来就是想知道
I'm calling to find out exactly what I need to do
我接下来具体应该怎么安排
to make arrangements for the next step.
我知道了 好的 谢谢
I see. Okay, thank you.
能给我一张餐巾纸吗
Can I have a napkin?
是的
Yes.
没错 但我不知道要怎么把他的...
That's right, so-- but what do I gotta do to get his--
把他的遗体
to get his body over the--
不好意思 钱德勒先生 能别在帕特里克面前说吗
excuse me, Mr. Chandler, i don't think Patrick needs to be here for this.
这没什么
Don't-- I'm all right.
好的 我懂了
I understand.
为什么运到曼彻斯特更贵
So why is it more to drive his body to Manchester?
因为要走七分钟的高速
So you gotta take the highway for seven minutes,
所以就更贵了?
that's why it costs more?
那如果灵车走127号公路多少钱
Well, what does it cost for the hearse to take 127?
天啊 他还在计较这些
Jesus, like, that's his focus?
没事
Jeez, I'm all right.
谢谢 李叔叔
Thanks, uncle Lee.
不用谢
You're welcome.
- 谢谢了 钱德勒先生      - 没事
- Thanks, Mr. Chandler.        - You're welcome.
那么
So...
我们先不说你上次爆粗口的事
We're gonna forget about the language.
也不提你上次动手打人的事
We're gonna forget about the fists.
但我想要你暂停几天训练
But I want you to take a few days off of practice.
你别来训练了
I don't want you on the ice.
实话说 先生
Well, to tell you the honest truth, sir,
我可以把训练当成分散注意力的方式
I could really use the distraction.
冰球不是一件让你分散注意力的事
The ice is not a distraction.
当你在冰上时 你要全身心投入
When you're on the ice, you gotta be there.
所以 休息几天吧
Okay, so take a couple days off,
然后我们再谈
and we'll talk.
听着
Listen.
我在像你这么大时 我也失去了我爸
When I was your age, i lost my dad, too.
所以
So...
我明白你经历了什么
I know what you're-- you're goin' through.
如果你想来说说话
If you want to come in and talk,
想找个人倾诉一下
or want somebody to spill your guts to,
或者你想找个人发泄发泄
or throw the bull around,
我随时欢迎你来
the door's open.
你介意我放点音乐吗
You mind if i put some music on?
不介意
No.
你喜欢这群人？
do you like these guys?
主音吉他有点弱
The lead guitar is weak,
但其他都挺好
but otherwise they're pretty good.
在我听起来 他们都一样
Oh, they all sound the same to me.
我们去哪
Where are we goin'?
去见律师
Gotta go to the lawyer.
去干嘛
What for?
我们要去看你爸的遗嘱
To read your father's will.
我一定得在场吗
Do I have to be there?
不一定 但我觉得你应该在场
I don't think so, but I think you're supposed to be.
你觉得他把船留给谁了
Who do you think he left the boat to?
我敢肯定他把什么都留给你了
I'm sure he left you everything.
我不明白
I don't understand.
哪个部分不明白
Which, uh, part are you having trouble with?
我没法当帕特里克的监护人
Well, I can't be the guardian.
这...
Well... uh--
我是说 我做不到
I mean, I can't.
我自然是认为
Well, naturally, i-- I assumed Joe had
乔已经和你讨论过这件事了
discussed all this with you.
没有
No.
他没说过
He didn't.
没有
No.
呃...我
Uh, i-- i--
不得不说 我还真有些吃惊了
sorry, I have to say, I'm somewhat taken aback.
他不能和我住一起 我只有一个房间
He can't live with me. I live in one room.
但乔提供了帕特里克之后的生活所需
Well, but Joe has provided for Patrick's upkeep.
食物啊 衣服啊等等
Food, clothes, etcetera.
房子和船都是他的
And the house and the boat are owned outright.
但我总不能在他18岁前
I can't commute from Boston every day
天天从波斯顿往这来回跑吧
until he turns 18.
我想也许你可以换个地方住
I think the idea was that you would relocate.
换去哪
R-- relocate to where?
你看看这写的
Well, you look-- - here?
你可以看得出来 你哥哥
Well, as you can see, your brother
把一切都安排得非常仔细
worked everything out extremely carefully.
- 但是他不可能      - 是的
- But he can't have--        - yes.
他不可能是那个意思
He can't have meant that.
他还拿出五千美元
Uh, he's allowed up to $5,000
作为你的搬家费
to pay for moving expenses.
你还有一小笔钱
And there's, uh-- there's also a small amount
可以支取
set aside for, uh, you know,
作为补贴
for you to draw from-- as personal income.
在你搬来之后
while you settle in.
当然是在你接受的前提下
I mean, assuming that you accept.
那唐尼叔叔和特蕾莎婶婶呢
What about my uncle Donny and aunt Teresa?
乔觉得帕特里克和他们
Joe didn't feel that Patrick really had any special relationship
- 没什么深厚的感情      - 我不明白
- or feeling about them--        - I don't understand.
我想你应该知道
And now, as I think you know,
他们现在好像搬去威斯康星州了
they've moved out to Wisconsin, I believe.
明尼苏达
Minnesota.
- 是明尼苏达      －明尼苏达州的明尼通卡
- Minnesota.        - Minnetonka, Minnesota.
是的
That's right.
我印象里你这些年在这待了不少时间
It was my impression that you'd spent a lot of time here over the years.
我只是个过来帮个忙
I was just the back up.
自从我爸照顾不了小帕之后
I came up here to look after Patty, yeah,
乔住院的时候我会过来照顾小帕
if Joe was in the hospital after my father couldn't do it,
但我们...
but we--
本来应该是唐尼来的
it was supposed to be Donny.
我只是来帮个忙
I'm just the back up.
我只能说 我 我
Well, i-- I can just repeat that I'm-- I'm...
真没想到乔没跟你说这件事
Astonished that Joe didn't run this by you,
毕竟他是个很周到的人
thorough as he was.
那是因为他知道问了我 我会怎么说
Yeah, 'cause he knew what I would say if he would have asked.
运气 你这是运气球
Once! It was once!
运气而已 就这么一次
Oh, one time nothin'. It's nothin' but one time.
小心这边的球
Stay out of this quadrant,
不然我会把你打哭
and you won't go home in tears.
好啊
All right.
嘿
Hey!
给我小点声音 你们这些蠢猪
You wanna keep it down, you fuckin' morons?
我的孩子们还在睡觉呢
My kids are sleepin'.
我很抱歉 我真心的 我没想到我们这么吵
I'm so sorry. I am-- I didn't think we were that loud.
李 能请你把这些混蛋
Lee. You wanna get these fuckin' pinheads
赶出我家吗
out of my house, please?
好 我会的
Yeah, I do.
兰迪 我会的
Randi, I really do.
她不能这样跟我们说话
She can't talk to us that way.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿
Hey!
我可没跟你们开玩笑
I'm not fuckin' around!
这他妈的都凌晨两点了
It's 2:00 in the fuckin' morning.
快让这群混蛋穿好衣服
Get these fuckin' assholes dressed,
然后他妈滚出去
and get 'em the fuck out of here!
我们都穿得好好的呢
We are dressed.
她不是故意的 她一会儿会道歉的
She didn't mean it. She'll apologize later.
得走了 哥们
Gotta get out of here, man.
- 回见      - 回见
- See ya later.        - Right on.
李
Lee.
- 谢了 哥们 保重      - 好
- Thanks, bro. Take care!        - All right!
- 帮我们向兰迪道个歉      - 晚安
- Tell Randi we're sorry.        - Good night!
- 别酒后驾驶      - 真不好意思
- Don't drink and drive.        - We're so sorry!
看见木星了吗
You see Jupiter?
喂 汤米
Hey, Tommy!
晚安 乔
Good night, Joe!
抱歉啊
Sorry again!
去吧 那是木星 你个白痴
Go ahead. It's Jupiter, you fuckin' idiot.
看见北极星了吗
Look at, there's the north star right there.
- 就在那      - 在哪
- Right there.        - Where?
就在正北方
It's-- it's due north.
我早上会打扫干净的
I'll clean up in the morning.
你能看见木星? 混蛋
You see Jupiter, you fuckin' asshole?
别这样
Come on.
去你的
Fuck you.
别这样
Come on.
李
Lee.
李 没人能体会你经历了什么
Lee, nobody can appreciate what you've been through.
如果我能这么说的话
If I can say that.
如果你真的觉得你做不到
And if you really feel like you can't take this on,
那是...
well, that's-- that's--
那也是你的权利
you know, that's your right.
- 显而易见      - 那谁来管他
- Obviously.        - So who would get him?
帕特里克 来罐苏打或别的什么吗
Patrick, can I get you a can of soda or anything?
不用了 谢谢你
No, thank you.
我不知道帕特里克的母亲现在怎么样了
Well, I don't know what's happening with Patrick's mother.
- 不行      - 我不知道她在哪
- No.        - I'm not sure where she is,
- 也不知道她现在是什么情况      - 不行
- or what kind of condition she's in.        - No.
我们不能那么做
We can't do that.
天啊 不要 天啊
God, no! Oh, god!
弗雷德 弗雷德 我的孩子还在里面
Fred! Fred! My kids are in there!
我的孩子还在里面
My kids are in there!
天啊 我的天啊
God! Oh, god!
我要进去
I gotta go in there.
这样吧 李
Look, Lee.
那要不你...
Why don't you just--
我们再联系吧
I'm gonna-- I'll be in touch.
我在这等你
Um, I'm here.
我们在聚会 玩得挺嗨
Well, we were partying pretty hard.
喝啤酒
And there was beer.
有人还带了大麻烟来
And someone was passin' around a joint,
还有可卡因
and there was cocaine.
可卡因？
Cocaine?
是的
Yes.
接着说
Okay, go ahead.
总之 我们的卧室在楼下
Uh, anyway, our bedroom is in the downstairs,
孩子们睡在楼上
and the kids sleep upstairs,
两点的时候兰迪把所有人都赶走了
so Randi makes everyone leave around 2:00.
也可能是三点
Or 3 A.M.
然后
And then...
她就回去睡觉了
She goes back to bed.
我到楼上看了看孩子们
So I go upstairs to check on the kids,
楼上太他妈冷了
and it's fuckin' freezin' upstairs,
但我不能开中央暖气
but I can't use the central heat
因为兰迪会鼻窦发干
'cause it dries out randi's sinuses,
然后就会头疼得很厉害
and gives her really bad headaches.
于是我下了楼 在壁炉里生了火
So I go downstairs and i put a fire in the fireplace,
然后坐下来看电视
and sit down and watch TV,
可是发现啤酒没了
but there's no more beer.
我还是冷得直跺脚
I'm still jumpin' around like... a jackrabbit,
所以我在火里又加了几块柴火
so I put a couple of fire logs in the fire,
这样就能趁我出门的时候把家里弄暖和点了
and i-- just to warm up the house while I was gone.
然后我去了趟小超市
And then i-- I'm goin' to the mini mart,
但是我喝得太醉了 所以不想开车
but I'm too wasted and i don't want to drive.
所以我走路过去 来回各二十分钟
So I walk, it's about 20 minutes each way.
大概走到半路时
I'm about halfway there,
我不记得我有没有把炉罩盖在炉子上了
and I can't remember if I put a screen on the fireplace.
但我想应该没事
I figure it's okay.
于是就继续往商店走了
So I just keep goin' to the store.
就这样了
And, uh, that's it.
应该是有一块木头滚到了地上
Log must have rolled out onto the floor.
消防员说他们把兰迪救出来了
Uh, fireman said they pulled Randi out.
她昏倒在楼下
She passed out downstairs.
然后炉子爆了
and then the furnace blew,
他们没法再进去一趟了
and they couldn't go back in again.
我就记得这么多了
That's all I remember.
好的 李 暂时就这样吧
Okay, Lee, that's all for now.
如果还有什么事要问你的话
We'll-- we'll call you if anything else comes up
我们会打电话给你的
we want to ask you about.
如果法医证实你说了的话
Assuming the forensics bear you out,
我想应该是没问题
which I'm assuming they will.
什么 这就完了？
So, uh, that's it?
听着 李 昨晚你犯了一个
Look, Lee, you made a horrible mistake.
所有人都可能会犯的致命错误
Like a million other people did last night.
但我们不会因此把你钉上十字架
Not gonna crucify you.
忘记把炉罩放回炉子里并不是罪
It's not a crime to forget to put the screen on the fireplace.
呃 我是说
Well, I mean, you know,
那我能走了？
so I can go?
除非有什么新情况 现在你可以走了
Well, if something comes up we don't already know about, yeah.
有人来接你回家吗
You got anyone to give you a ride back home?
乔来了吗 你爸爸来了吗
Is Joe here? Is your dad here?
来了
Yeah.
- 抱歉      - 那好
- Sorry.        - Okay.
孩子
Son!
放下枪 放下枪
Put it down. Put it down!
按在地上 按在地上
Get on the ground. Get on the ground.
- 拜托      - 冷静点 冷静点
- Ah, please!        - Settle down. Settle down.
- 拿手铐来      - 别起来
- We need some cuffs right now.        - Stay down.
- 别起来      - 按住 把他按在地上
- Stay down.        - Down, down, get him down.
好了 我们走吧
All right, let's go.
再见
Bye.
我们去哪 孤儿院吗
Where we goin', to the orphanage?
- 闭嘴      - 我干嘛了我
- Shut up.        - What the hell did I do?
安静一会
Just be quiet.
我们还有很多事要做
All right, we got a lot to do.
- 船怎么办      - 我们可以和乔治讨论这件事
- What about the boat?        - We can talk to George about it.
如果没人要用的话
There's no use hangin' onto it
- 也没必要留着它了      - 我会用的
- if no one's gonna use it.        - I'm gonna use it.
- 它还得经常保养      - 我在保养
- It's gotta be maintained.        - I'm maintaining it.
- 我以后都会保养它的      - 你自己一个人可做不了
- I'm gonna maintain it.        - You can't maintain it by yourself.
为什么不行 它现在是我的船了 不是吗
Why not? It's my boat now, isn't it?
因为你还是个未成年人 你无法单独所有
'Cause you're a minor, you can't take it out alone.
我是托管人
I'm-- I'm the trustee.
- 我得去给你买单      -  托管人是什么意思
- I gotta make the payments--        - what does trustee mean?
跟进所有的检查
I gotta keep up the inspections.
意思是你的所有事情都由我来负责直到...
It means I'm in charge of handling everything for you until--
是不是说我不想让你卖 你也可以卖
does that mean you're allowed to sell the boat if I don't want you to?
直到你十八岁成年
Until you turn 18. I don't know.
我肯定会这么考虑的
I'll definitely consider it.
- 想都别想      - 别对你自己太自信了
- No fuckin' way.        - You're so goddamn sure of yourself.
- 我们没人去经营它 你才十六岁      - 我今年可以拿到执照
- There's no one to run it. You're 16 years old.        - I get my license this year.
那又怎么样 你还是个未成年人
Doesn't matter, you're still a minor.
你不能独自经营商业用船
You can't run a commercial vessel by yourself.
而且这还是很大一笔开销 我才是那个付钱的人
Meanwhile, it's a big fuckin' expense, and I'm the one that's gotta manage it,
- 而且我都没法待在这里      - 谁他妈在乎你在哪
- and I'm not gonna be here.        - Who gives a fuck where you are?
小帕 我对天发誓我会打爆你的头
Patty, I swear to god, I'm gonna knock your fuckin' block off.
- 真是个好爸爸      - 什么 你说什么
- Great parenting.        - What? What'd you say?
- 我说 真是个好爸爸      - 我操
- I said great parenting.        - Fuck you!
管好你自己的事 你个混球
Mind your fuckin' business, you fuckin' asshole!
你要冲我脸上来一拳吗
You're gonna smash me in the face.
嘿 没事了 没事了 没事了
Hey, it's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
- 没事了 没事了      - 你要冲我脸上来一拳?
- It's okay, it's okay.        - You want me to smash your fuckin' face,
- 你个混球      - 没事了 没事了
- you fuckin' asshole.        - It's okay. It's okay.
谢谢 谢谢 没事了
Thank you. Thank you. It's okay.
李叔叔 你彻底发疯吗
Uncle Lee, are you fundamentally unsound?
给我他妈的上车
Get in the fuckin' car.
你不开门我可没法照做
Can't obey your orders until you unlock the door.
闭上你的嘴
Shut up.
虽然这个发动机一时半会还坏不了
It's not like the motor's gonna die tomorrow,
但乔说它就像个混蛋一样总是掉链子
but Joe said it keeps breakin' down like a son of a bitch.
嗯 但我们还是要看一下
Yeah, but we were gonna take a look--
虽然我们有那么一笔钱
see, there's an allotment of some kind, but--
这个周末要看一下
take a look this weekend.
但这事还不一定
Things are a little bit up in the air.
不 我会负责的
No, i-- I can take care of it
做做日常保养什么的
as far as the general maintenance is concerned,
但发动机总有一天会坏的
but that motor's gonna go at some point.
我会负责的
I'm taking care of it.
没有留出来买新发动机的钱
There's no allotment for a new motor.
除非...乔治 你认识谁想要把它买走的吗
Unless, George, you know someone who wants to buy it.
等一下 我不卖
Wait a second, I'm not selling it.
反正我们要去波士顿的
We're gonna be in Boston, anyway.
什么
What?!
我什么时候得待在波士顿了
Since when are we supposed to be in Boston?
别一惊一乍的
Just take it easy.
不管你怎么决定的
Well, whatever you decide,
光把它搁在那就能搁到你破产
it's gonna bleed you dry just sittin' here.
我们还没决定到底要怎么办
Well, we don't know exactly what we're doin'.
你知道的 他随时可以过来住我们这
Well, you know, he can always stay with us
你如果他想周末来玩玩的话
if he wants to come up weekends.
你想当他的监护人吗
Do you want to be his guardian?
- 那个...我们已经      - 他又不想当我的监护人
- Well, we already--        - he doesn't want to be my guardian,
我的天啊
for Christ sakes.
- 这段时间有些孩子该离开家了      - 你去他家看过吗
- We're tryin' to lose some kids at this point.        - Have you seen his house?
- 是啊      - 没去过 我们现在要厘清这些杂事
- Yeah.        - No, we're tryin' to work out the logistics,
- 我也不知道      - 我们家确实很挤
- so I don't know--        - we're jammed in there pretty good,
- 但是我们...      - 天呐 能别说了吗
- but we--        - Jesus Christ, will you stop?
但我们家的沙发总会留给他 只要他愿意 随时都可以
We've always got a sofa for him any time he wants.
- 乔治      - 你明白的 对吧
- George--        - you know that, right?
没事 我明白
That's all right, i know-- I know that.
- 我们随时都欢迎他      - 我明白
- He's welcome any time.        - I understand.
我明白 谢谢你
I-- I know. Thank you.
你脑子坏了吗
Are you brain damaged?
你不能和别人这么说
You can't just talk to people like that.
你不想当我的监护人 这对我来说没什么
You don't want to be my guardian, that's fine with me.
不是这个问题 这只是些杂事
It's not that, it's just the logistics.
我得理理清楚 我发誓
I've just gotta work it all out, i swear.
怎么做 把我送去明尼苏达州瓦卡汤卡
How? My takin' me to wonkatonka, Minnesota,
- 唐尼叔叔那里?      - 是明尼通卡
- with uncle Donny?        - Minnetonka.
- 明尼苏达的明尼通卡      - 好吧 明尼苏达的明尼通卡
- Minnetonka, Minnesota.        - Okay, minnetonka, Minnesota.
有什么区别
Same difference.
那我妈不行吗
What about my mother?
法官不会把你给她
The judge would never let that happen.
再说没人知道她在哪
And anyway, no one even knows where she is.
我知道
I do.
她在康涅狄格州
She's in Connecticut.
至少去年是在那里
At least she was last year.
你什么时候知道的
Since when do you know that?
她去年给我发邮件了
Well, she emailed me last year,
所以我给她回信了
so I emailed her back.
你知道吗 邮件
You know email?
你爸知道你跟她还有联系吗
Did your father know you were in touch with her?
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我们能边走边说吗 我快冻死了
Can we walk? I'm freezing.
- 关于她 我只知道...      - 我知道 我知道 我知道
- All I know is--        - I know, I know, I know.
她是个酒鬼 是个疯子
She's a drunk, she's insane,
让狗在地板上拉屎
she let the dog shit on the floor.
这是你爸
It's the last thing that your father
最不愿意看到的
ever would have wanted.
你什么时候开始在乎他的想法了
Oh! Oh, like suddenly you care what he would have wanted.
现在去哪
Where to now?
- 殡仪馆      - 好极了
- The funeral parlor.        - Great.
哇 我们这是去哪
Whoa, whoa, whoa, where are we--where are we goin'?
他在比弗利的殡仪馆
He's in Beverly.
曼彻斯特连殡仪馆都没有？
There's no funeral homes in Manchester?
没有
Nope.
墓碑会在这
The cemetery's here.
让我们把这事给完成了吧
Let's just get this done.
冬天有很多人取南方避寒
Down south, we got a lot of snowbirds.
年初 人们从北边往南边走
Early in the year, people from the north head down there,
有人就在那里过世了 虽然不是那边的人
they die down there, they're not from the area.
那跟我们有什么关系
What do they even like about us?
- 都是为爱的人办理后事      - 是啊
- Makin' arrangements for a loved one.        - Right.
很多时候 人们来我们这里
A lot of times, people are comin' in,
- 这可以说是他们最不喜欢的事了      - 没错
- last thing they had on their mind.        - Right.
有时候 我发现虽然家庭内部不太和谐
Sometimes I find there's dysfunction in the family still,
但通常人们还是会出席葬礼的
somehow people come together. You know?
那家伙严肃又忧郁的样子是怎么回事
Dude, what is with that guy and the big serious and somber act?
我不知道
I don't know.
说真的 难道他意识不到
No, but seriously, does he not realize
大家都知道他每天都这么做吗
that people know he does this every single day?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们为什么不能安葬他
Why can't we bury him?
天气太冷 地面太硬了
Too cold. The ground is too hard.
要到春天再下葬
They'll bury him in the spring.
所以在那之前 他们会拿他怎么样
So what do they do with him until then?
把他放在冰柜里
Put him in a freezer.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
没错
Yes.
这可真吓到我了
That really freaks me out.
这没什么的
It doesn't matter.
等等
Wait a minute.
我想我把车停在另一边了 抱歉
I think I parked the car the other way. Sorry.
那用小型蒸汽挖土机行吗
What about one of those mini steam shovels?
什么
What?
有一次我在纽黑文的墓园
I once saw one of those mini steam shovels
见过一种小型蒸汽挖土机
one time in a graveyard in New Haven.
两秒钟就能挖出一个完整的坑
It's like a perfect little hole in about two seconds.
我不知道要去哪里弄一把来
Well, I don't really know how to get a hold of one
也不知道要花多少钱
or how much it would cost.
我们不能考虑一下吗
Why can't we just look into it?
你不能在罗斯代尔历史公墓
Because you can't use heavy equipment
使用重型设备
in the historic rosedale cemetery.
为什么不能
Why not?
因为有很多重要人物
Because there are very important people
埋葬在那里
who are buried there,
他们的子孙不想让蒸汽挖土机
and their descendants don't want steam shovels
在他们的墓地上震动
vibrating over their dead bodies.
那为什么我们不能换个地方下葬
Well, why can't we just bury him someplace else?
因为乔买的就是这个地方
Because that's the plot that Joe bought.
别问我为什么
Don't ask me why.
但如果你想要有其它安排
But if you want to make some other arrangements,
你想另找地方安葬他
you want to find someplace else to bury him,
你想和殡葬人员谈
you want to talk to the mortician,
你想打电话给神圣之心
and you want to call up sacred heart
和马丁神父谈话
and talk to father Martin
弄明白这些要花多少钱
and find out how much that's gonna cost
然后安排这一切的话
and make all those arrangements,
随你来 否则你就别管
be my guest. Otherwise, let's just leave it.
我只是不想让他待在冰柜里
I just don't like him being in a freezer.
是啊
Yeah.
我也不想
I don't like it, either,
但那不是他 他已经离开了
but it isn't him because he's gone.
那只是他的遗体
It's just his body.
我只想说 我有点被吓坏了
I'm just saying it kind of freaks me out.
妈的 我到底把这该死的车停在哪里了
Oh, god damn it, where did I park the car?
我不知道 但愿你能想起来
Yeah, I don't know, but i wish you'd figure it out
因为我现在快被冻死了
because I'm freezing my ass off.
你没件像样的冬衣吗
You don't have a normal winter coat?
有啊 我有的
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
你为什么不戴双能套住手指的手套
Why don't you wear gloves with the real fingers on them?
妈的
Oh, god, fuck.
操 我他妈到底把这该死的车停在哪里了
Oh, fuck, where did I park this motherfucking car?
真他妈冷
God damn, it's cold.
怎么 你的冬季夹克不保暖吗
Why? What's the matter with your winter jacket?
- 你认真的吗 小帕      - 快把暖气打开
- Seriously, Patty?        - Just turn the heat on.
已经开了
It's on already.
那再开大一点
Well, turn it up a little.
已经开到最大了
It's all the way up.
它在朝我吹冷气呢
It's blowing freezing air on me.
等一分钟就会暖和起来
It just needs a minute to warm up.
你什么时候买的这破车 1928年吗
What year did you get this thing, 1928?
随车附赠的那匹马在哪呢
Where's the horse that goes with this fucking car?
没准它还能朝我们吹点热气
Maybe he can breathe on us.
小帕 别逼我
Patty, I swear to god.
我知道 怎么不把我爸在这破车上
I know. Why don't we keep my dad in here
放三个月
for the next three months?
还能给你省一大笔钱
You'd save a fucking fortune.
冰柜的事你能闭嘴吗
Would you shut the fuck up about the freezer?
你想让我就被一个葬礼和那几个殡仪员
Want me to have a nervous breakdown
弄到精神崩溃吗
because there's undertakers and a funeral?
- 谁在乎      - 不 我没这么想
- Who cares?        - No. I don't.
好了 暖和一点了
Okay, it's getting warmer.
我有个乐队排练 你能送我回家
I got band practice. Can you drive me home
好让我拿上东西
so I can get my stuff
然后再送我去我女朋友家吗
and take me over to my girlfriend's house?
当然
Sure.
这是来过家里的那个女孩吗
This the same girl who was over at the house?
不 那是希尔薇 这是桑迪
No. That was Sylvie, and this is Sandy.
她们都不知道对方的存在
They don't know about each other,
所以什么都别说
so, uh, please don't say anything
以防被拆穿
in case it comes up.
我不会说
I won't.
你真的和这两个女孩都上过床吗
Do you actually have sex with these girls?
难道盖上棉被纯聊天吗
We don't just play computer games.
两个都有吗
With both of them?
桑迪的妈妈在
Well, with Sandy's mom here,
所以有点不方便 就像搞地下活动一样
it's sort of, uh, strictly just like basement business.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我正在想办法
It means I'm working on it.
停 奥托 你怎么回事
Stop. Otto, man, what are you doing?
我怎么了
What did I do?
你慢太多了 兄弟
You're way behind, man.
不 我没有
No, I'm not.
你有点没跟上 奥托
You're a little behind, Otto.
你应该紧跟贝斯来 奥托
You got to stay with the bass, Otto.
别这样 兄弟 你跟紧我 好吗
Come on, man, just stay with me, all right?
- 开始吧     - 好吧 抱歉
- Let's go.        - All right, I'm sorry.
没事 来吧
All right. Yeah. Come on.
没事
It's all right.
来吧 开始
Come on, let's go.
- 好了 大伙      - 再来一遍
- All right, guys.        - Let's go again.
奥托 你可以了吗
Otto, you good?
- 准备好了吗 哥们      - 来吧 亲爱的
- You good, buddy?        - Let's go, baby.
我们是 响彻云霄
We are Stentorian.
一 二 三
1 2 3
嗨 你是李吗
Hi. Are you Lee?
我是吉尔 桑迪的妈妈
I'm Jill, Sandy's mom.
我想他们的排练快结束了
I think they're wrapping up.
你想进去喝杯啤酒什么的吗
You want to come inside and have a beer or something?
不用了 谢谢
It's all right. Thank you.
我想向你表达我对乔的悼念之情
I wanted to offer my condolences about Joe.
他是个很好的人
He was a terrific guy.
像他那样的好人现在已经很少了
There's not too many like him.
他是个很棒的父亲
He was a wonderful father.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我正想问帕特里克
I was-- I was going to ask Patrick
要不要留下来吃饭
if he wants to stay for supper,
如果你同意的话
if that's okay with you.
你想一起吃吗 我饭菜做太多了
You want to join us? I made way too much.
没事
That's all right.
我一会儿再回来接他
I'll just come back and get him.
什么时候 我什么时候过来
What time... What time should I come back?
我不知道 九点 或者九点半吧
Oh, I don't know. 9, 9:30.
他们要一起写作业 应该吧
They're going to do their homework together, supposedly.
哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha.
好吧 我九点半再过来
All right. I'll come back at 9:30.
好吧 要是你十分钟之内改主意了
Okay. When you change your mind in the next ten minutes,
我们就在屋里
we're right inside.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
老天 这个要怎么解开
Jesus Christ, how do you unbuckle this?
我手指都要蹭破皮了
I'm scraping the skin off my knuckles.
停下 把你的手拿出来
Hold on. Just take your hand out.
能请你
Would you please
把手从我下面挪开吗
just take your hand out of my cunt?
好 好
Okay. Okay.
我们现在要脱裤子吗
Oh, are we taking our pants off?
我是要脱裤子了
I'm taking my pants off.
我不知道你在干嘛
I don't know what you're doing.
那我也要脱裤子
I'm taking my pants off.
快点
Come on.
你得先脱掉你的鞋子
You got to take your show off first.
- 天呐      - 我在脱呢
- Jesus.        - I'm-- I'm trying.
孩子们 快下来吃饭了
Hey, kids, come on, have some dinner.
谢谢 妈 我们马上就下来
Thanks, mom. We'll be right down.
谢谢 吉尔 马上
Thanks, Jill. One second.
我得先退出
I just got to log off.
你能别演了吗 她又不是弱智
Would you shut up? She's not retarded.
你为什么要和我过不去
Why are you picking on me?
我没有和你过不去
I'm not picking on you.
你在给我惹麻烦
You'll get me in trouble.
我没有给你惹麻烦
I'm not going to get in trouble.
那你是想做什么
What are you trying to do?
数学作业做得怎么样了
How's the math homework?
挺好的
It's good.
挺失败的
Very frustrating.
很好
Good.
那些算法真是折磨死人
Those algorithms are a bitch.
这个真的很好吃 吉尔
This is really good, Jill.
- 谢谢你 帕特里克      - 这是...
- Thank you, Patrick.        - Is this a--
这是自制培根意面酱吗
this is a homemade carbonara sauce?
天了 闭嘴吧
Jesus, shut up.
不是
No.
你不说我还以为是呢
You could have fooled me.
老天
Jesus.
什么 怎么了
What? What?
你真是个马屁精
You're such a kiss-ass.
- 桑迪      - 怎么了
- Sandy!        - What,
我不就是夸你妈的厨艺好吗
because I appreciate your mother's cooking?
- 晚安      - 晚安
- Good night.        - Good night.
你都不问我发生了什么吗
Aren't you going to ask what happened?
- 我不想知道      - 我猜也不想
- I don't want to know.        - Guess not.
加把劲啊
Come on.
你好
Hello.
你好 是李吗
Hello. Lee?
我是兰迪
It's Randi.
- 你好      - 是 抱歉 我在
- Hello?         - Yeah. Sorry. I'm here.
- 你好 你怎么样      - 我很好 你好吗
- Hi. How are you?        - Okay. How are you?
- 挺好的      - 好吧
- Good.        - Good.
我打来是因为
I was just calling--
乔治告诉了我乔的事情
George  told me about Joe,
我只想打来说声节哀顺变
and I just wanted to call  and say I'm sorry.
我希望你不介意我打来
I hope you don't mind  me calling.
不会 没事 谢谢你
No. It's fine. Thank you.
我不介意 你怎么样
I don't mind. How are you?
我现在挺难过的
Not so good right now.
我想我们都预料到这件事
I guess we should have seen it coming,
但是 还是有点让人不敢相信
but it's still hard to believe.
- 是啊      - 是啊
- Yeah.        - Yeah.
- 帕特里克怎么样      - 他还好
- How's Patrick doing?        - He's good.
只是表面上看起来吧
Beyond the obvious,  obviously.
他还好 他没事 我也不知道
He's okay. He's fine. I don't know.
不过你也知道 孩子都很难懂
You know how kids are. It's hard to tell.
他不太对我敞开心扉
He doesn't really open up with me,
但他看起来没事 他有一大群朋友
but he seems fine. He's got a lot of friends.
- 那很好      - 是的
- Oh, well, that's good.         - Yeah, it is.
所以 我不知道你有没有准备好举行葬礼
So I don't know if you'd planned a service yet,
但我想问 要是你不介意的话
but I was also going to ask,  if you wouldn't mind,
我想去参加葬礼 可以吗
I'd like to be there if it's okay with you.
没事 我不介意
Yeah, it's fine. I don't mind.
那好 谢谢你
Okay, okay. Thank you.
这对我来说意义重大
It would mean a lot to me.
没事 你应该来的
No, you should come.
我会通知你时间
I'll let you know when it's going to be.
谢谢你
Thank you.
所以我能问你
So can I ask, uh...
你还好吗
How are you?
我不知道 你还好吗
I don't know. How are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们都还挺好
We're doing pretty well.
我想我应该告诉你
I should probably tell you.
我要当...
I'm going to be a--
其实 我怀孕了
actually,  I'm-- I'm pregnant.
- 是吗      - 是啊
- Oh, yeah?        - Yeah.
而且 就快要生了
You know, like, ready to pop.
我还真不知道
Oh, I didn't know that.
我不知道是不是应该和你说
Uh, I didn't know if I should tell you,
但是
but...
没事 没关系 祝贺你
No, it's fine. Congratulations.
谢谢你  你见到我的时候
Thank you. You would probably deduce it for yourself
也能看出来
when you see me.
是啊
Yeah.
所以
So, uh, you know,
我只是想说 那个...
I just wanted to say,  you know--
我想说 对不起
actually, uh, i-- oh, sorry.
我不是有意挂你电话 我还有事
I didn't mean to cut you off. I just got to go.
没事 我只想打来确认一下
I just wanted to make  sure it's okay
我和乔希是不是方便参加葬礼
if me and Josh come to the funeral.
- 完全没问题      - 谢谢你 李
- It's totally okay.        - Thank you, Lee.
好的 上帝保佑
Okay. God bless.
- 再会      - 再见
- So long.        - Bye.
你在开玩笑吗 我从来都没去过波士顿
Are you kidding me? I've never even been to Boston.
哦 那挺好的 你和帕特里克
Oh, it's great, you and Patrick.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
所以 你还好吗
So how are you holding up?
- 有什么事吗      - 噢
- What's the matter?        - Ohh.
我就是问 你还好吗
I said how are you holding up?
这是个白痴问题 你吃什么了吗
It's a stupid question. Get some food?
我吃了点奶酪
Oh, uh, i had some cheese.
你就吃了点奶酪吗 混蛋
You had some cheese, asshole?
我给你弄点东西来
I'll get you something.
- 我什么都不想吃      - 珍妮
- I don't want anything.        - Hey, Janine!
- 你确定吗      - 怎么了
- Sure?        - What?
- 我什么都不想吃      - 没什么
- I don't want anything.        - Never mind.
- 怎么了      - 没事 忽略我
- What?        - Forget it. Skip it.
你说的我一句也听不见
I can't hear a goddamn word you're saying.
什么
What?
李吃东西了吗
Did Lee get food?
他没有 什么
He didn't-- what?
李吃东西了吗
Did Lee get food?
没有 他不想吃
No! He doesn't want any.
- 没事      - 我给他拿点东西
- We're good.        - I'll make him a plate.
别管了 他不要
Forget it. He doesn't--
没事了
we're fine.
他什么都不想吃
He doesn't want any--
我叫希尔薇来过夜可以吗
hey, is it okay if i invite Sylvie over?
她是哪一个来着
Which one is she?
褐色头发那个
She's the one with the... The brown hair.
不行
No.
不行是什么意思
What do you mean, no?
我不喜欢她
I don't like her.
我不想让她现在出现在我家
I don't want her in the house right now.
为什么 你连话都不用和她说
Why not? You don't even have to talk to her.
不好意思 你可以去她家 或者找你朋友
Sorry. Go to her house or call one of your friends.
就这样
That's that.
如果我过去 你妈同意吗
Would it be cool with your mom if I came over there?
我不知道
I have no idea.
好吧 明天联系
Okay. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
好吧 我也不能去她家
Well, I can't stay there, either.
那就对不起了
Sorry about that.
你要在这过夜吗
You going to stay in here?
是啊 怎么了
Yeah. Why not?
我想可能你会想睡在我爸的房间
I thought maybe you'd want to stay in dad's room.
怎么 你希望我睡那吗
Why, do you want me to?
没 只是那个房间比较好
No. It's just a better room.
而且现在也空着
And he's not using it.
好吧 我睡你爸的房间
Okay. I'll stay in there.
反正我们也不会在这里待多久了
We're not gonna be here that much longer anyway.
我不会搬去波士顿的 李叔叔
We're not moving to Boston, uncle Lee.
我现在不想谈论这个问题
Well, I don't want to talk about that right now.
你说他留了钱 让你好搬过来
You said he left you money so you could move.
是 那不见得...
Yeah. That doesn't mean--
况且 你在波士顿有什么
anyway, what's in Boston?
你只是个清洁工
You're a janitor.
- 那怎么了      - 你在哪儿不能当清洁工
- So what?        - You can do that anywhere.
这里到处都是厕所
There's plenty of toilets
和堵塞的水槽
and clogged-up drains all over town.
- 我不想...      - 我所有的朋友都在这里
- I don't want to--        - all my friends are here.
我加入了冰球队
I'm on the hockey team.
我加入了篮球队
I'm on the basketball team.
我现在还要保养我们的船
I got to maintain our boat now.
我每周有两天要去乔治的船上帮忙
I work on George's boat two days a week.
我有两个女朋友
I got two girlfriends,
我还加入了乐队
and I'm in a band.
你只是昆西的一个清洁工
You're a janitor in Quincy.
你他妈有什么好在乎自己住在哪里的
What the hell do you care where you live?
我要去睡了
I got to go to sleep.
晚安
Good night.
你今晚住哪
Where are you going to stay tonight?
我不知道 汽车旅馆吧
I don't know. A motel.
你什么时候该给我打电话
What time you going to call me?
我到旅馆的时候
When I get to the motel.
如果我到了九点还没你消息
I want to hear from you by 9:00,
我就会报警
or I'm going to call the cops.
- 明白吗      - 明白 明白
- Understand?        - Yes. Yes.
帕特里克 来跟你李叔叔说再见
Patrick, come say goodbye to your uncle Lee!
- 没关系      - 不 有关系
- It's okay.        - No, it's not.
帕特里克
Patrick!
来了
Coming!
我会来看他的
I'm going to see him.
再见 李叔叔
Goodbye uncle Lee.
再会
So long.
小帕
Patty?
我有点不太对劲
I think there's something wrong with me.
什么意思 你病了吗
What do you mean? Like what? Are you sick?
我不知道
I don't know!
- 我感觉非常奇怪      - 你生病了吗
- I feel really weird!        - Are you sick?
我突然觉得很恐慌
I think I'm havin' a panic attack.
什么意思
What do you mean? Hey.
我不知道 我感觉...
I don't know, I mean...
你能把那该死的东西弄出去吗
Could you get that shit outta here, please?
把什么弄出来
Get rid of what?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know, I don't know!
吃的吗
The food?
你想让我把那些吃的给扔了吗
You want me to get rid of the food?
帕特里克 喂
Patrick? Hey.
你要我带你去医院吗
Do you want me to take you to the hospital?
不要 我不知道
No. I don't know.
你要我打给你朋友吗
Do you want me to call your friends?
- 我不知道      - 你想让我做什么
- I don't know.        - What do you want me to do?
小帕 你要睡了吗
Patty, are you going to bed?
别管我
Leave me alone.
我觉得我不能让你关着门
I don't think I should let you keep the door shut.
走开
Just go away.
我会走的 你把门打开
I will. Just open up the door.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
天哪 你有毛病吗
Jesus Christ, what's your problem?
我说了 把门打开 你是崩溃了吗
I said open up the door. Are you havin' a breakdown?
我要带你去医院吗
Shall we take you to the hospital?
不用 不用 不用
No! No! No!
我只是抓狂了
I'm just freakin' out.
好 没事 但是我不能让你关着门抓狂
Okay, fine, but I can't let you freak out with the door closed.
而且如果你每次看到冰冻的鸡都要抓狂的话
And if you're gonna freak out every time you see a frozen chicken
我想我们应该去医院看看
I think we should go to the hospital.
我对这种情况一无所知
I don't know anything about this.
我只是不想让他待在冰柜里
I just don't like him bein' in the freezer!
你已经表达地很清楚了
You've expressed that very clearly.
我也不想
I don't like it either.
但是我们什么办法都没有
There's nothin' we can do about it.
我不会烦你 我就坐在这
I'm not gonna bother you. I'm just gonna sit here
等你稍微好点了我就走
until you calm down.
好了 我现在好点了
All right, I'm calmer now.
所以你可以出去了吗
Can you please just go away?
不行
No.
好酷
Cool!
他们给你发多少工资
How much are they payin' you?
最低工资加这个房间
Minimum wage plus the room.
好吧
All right.
咱们去买点家具回来
Let's go get some furniture.
我有家具了
I got furniture.
你才没有
No, you don't.
这也算家具吗
This doesn't count as furniture.
这连个房间都不算
This is not a room.
咱们一块儿去买点家具吧
Let's go get some furniture
别烦我
get off my back.
小帕 过来 走吧
Patty, come on. Let's go.
走吧
Let's go.
放这儿
There we go.
好了
All right.
好多了吧?
Better?
好多了
Better.
听着
So, listen.
在你放假之前 我们都可以待在这
We can stay here until your school lets out.
好吗
Okay?
这样我也有时间把波士顿那边安排好
That'll give me time to set things up in Boston better.
暑假的时候你也可以跟着乔治干点什么
Maybe you can do some stuff with George in the summer if you want,
这样你就不会一夜之间就告别了原来的生活
and you don't get jerked out of your life overnight.
行吗
Okay?
你是在问我的意见还是在告诉我呢
Are you askin' me or tellin' me?
我是在告诉你我只能做到这样了
I'm tellin' you that's the best I can do.
那问我行不行还有什么必要呢
Then what the fuck do you care whether it's okay with me or not?
波士顿离这里只有四十五分钟车程而已
It's 45 minutes away.
想回来随时都行
You can come back here any time you want.
- 从昆西?      - 没错
- From Quincy?        - Yeah.
起码要一个半小时好吗 你是在跟我开玩笑吗
It's an hour and a-- is that a joke?
起码一个半小时的车程
It's an hour and a half at least!
- 不是的      - 而且还会堵车
- No, it's not.        - You gotta include the other cars!
从这到罗克斯伯里不可能只用半个小时
You couldn't get from here to Roxbury in half an hour
你他妈开个宇宙飞船都没那么快
if you flew in a fuckin' spaceship!
好吧 去你的
Okay, fuck it.
给我午饭钱
I need lunch money.
- 嘿 帕特里克     - 嘿 帕特里克
- Hey, Patrick!        - Hey, Patrick!
- 嘿 帕特里克      - 帕特里克 帕特里克
- Hey, Patrick!        - Patrick! Patrick!
你要去看福音吗
So, are you going to Godspell?
我正想着呢
I'm thinking about it.
好啊 拜
All right, 'Kay. Bye.
这俩也是你女朋友吗
Those your girlfriends, too?
她们倒是想
They wish.
你给乔治帮忙 他不是会给你钱的吗
Doesn't George give you money for working on his boat?
是啊 我存着呢
Yeah, but I'm savin' that.
- 存着干嘛      - 买新发动机
- For what?        - New motor.
你是要去看福音吗
You going to Godspell?
天呐
Aw, come on.
别吵了
Aw, come on!
你好
Hello.
嗨 是李吗
Hello, Lee?
李?
Lee?
李 是李吗
Lee, is that you?
能听见吗
Hello?
你的手怎么了
What happened to your hand?
不小心划伤的
I cut it.
说得好像我看不出来一样
Oh. For a minute there i didn't know what happened.
你凭什么不告诉我
Is there some reason why you didn't tell me
我妈打电话来了
my mom tried to call me?
她还说你把她电话给挂了
She wrote me you hung up on her.
她现在在埃塞克斯
She's in Essex.
想让我过去吃个饭 见见她的未婚夫
She wants me to come have lunch and meet her fiancée.
你是怎么想的
What'd you think?
是觉得她不能联系我吗
She couldn't get in touch with me?
我挂她电话是因为我不知道怎么跟她说
I hung up on her because i didn't know what to say to her.
我没告诉你是因为我不知道怎么跟你说
And I didn't tell you because 'cause I didn't know what to say to you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不能阻止我跟她来往
You can't stop me talkin' to her.
我才懒得管你
I don't give a shit what you do.
说得好听 你都不让我女朋友来过夜
No, but you won't let my girlfriend stay over,
你就这么讨厌我妈
You hate my mother so much
讨厌到连她打电话来了都不告诉我
you won't even tell me she called.
你宁愿把我拖到到昆西去 毁了我的人生
You'd rather drag me back to Quincy and ruin my life
也不愿意让别人当我的监护人
than let somebody else be my guardian--
没有别人了
there is nobody else.
我可以跟我妈在埃塞克斯生活
I can live in Essex with my mom.
不 不行
No, you can't.
她已经不酗酒了 而且她想让我过去
She's not an alcoholic anymore and she wants me
那所有的问题都迎刃而解了
to stay with her, then that solves all our problems.
我还是可以坐原来的巴士去现在的学校
I can take the same bus to my same school
我可以不用换新朋友
and keep all my friends,
还能留下我的船 你就可以回波士顿去了
and the boat, and you can go back to Boston,
愿意的话可以抽空回来看看我什么的都行
and still check in on me, or whatever, if you want to...
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
为什么
Why not?
小帕 我很抱歉挂了她的电话
Patty, I'm sorry I hung up on her.
我待会儿给她回一个过去
I'll call her back,
如果她跟我说话还有点人样
and if she seems semi-human to me,
我会让你去跟她和她未婚夫一起吃饭
you can go have lunch with her and her fiancée.
就这样
That's it.
我不想再谈这件事了
I don't wanna talk about this anymore.
好的 等前面没船了
Okay, soon as we're clear,
就打开发动机看看
open it up and we'll see what we can do.
好
Okay.
李
Oh. Lee?
- 嘿      - 嘿 最近怎么样啊
- Hey.        - Hey, what do you say?
- 还好吗      - 我还行 你呢
- How are you?        - Yeah, I'm good. How are you?
- 还行      - 嗯
- All right.        - Yeah.
乔的事我很抱歉
I'm really, uh-- I'm really sorry to hear about Joe.
没事 多谢
I know, yeah, thanks.
帕特里克怎么样
How's Patrick doing?
- 还好      - 是吗
- Good.        - Yeah?
- 是啊      - 那就好
- Yeah.        - Good.
最近在忙什么呢
What's going on? What are ya--
我最近回来了 打算待到暑假
you know, I'm back, I'm thinking about staying until the summer.
你这边还缺不缺人手
I was wondering if you had any work.
我想找点活干干
I'm looking to pick up some hours.
当然可以了
Sure, sure, um...
沃尔特现在刚好到波士顿去了
Walt is down in Boston, so...
- 是吗      - 如果你想过来的话
- Oh, he is?        - Yeah, he should be back tomorrow
- 他明天下午应该回来了      - 他明天回来是吗
- if you want to come by.        - He's coming back up tomorrow?
给他打个电话吧
Yeah, yeah. Give him a call.
好 我会的
Okay. I will give him a call.
- 好主意      - 我会的
- That's a good idea.        - I'll do that.
- 好      - 那行
- Absolutely.        - Okay. All right.
- 好      - 见到你很高兴
- All right.        - Good to see you.
- 谢了 杰瑞      - 没事
- Thanks, Jerry.        - All right.
我不想在这再见到他
I don't want to see him in here again.
再见 帕特里克
Bye, Patrick.
星期天想去看球赛吗
Want to watch the football game on Sunday?
- 好啊      - 再会 帕特里克
- Sure.        - So long, Patrick.
- 再见 帕特里克      - 再见
- Bye, Patrick.        - See you guys.
发动机怎么样了
How's the motor?
乔治说现在活塞随时都可能打穿气缸
George says the piston's gonna go right through the block any minute now.
很不幸 这就真是个问题了
Unfortunately that's a problem.
如果我们没法让船跑起来的话 我们就养不起它了
We can't afford to keep a boat if we can't run it,
而且要是发动机坏了 船就别想跑起来了
and we can't run it if it's got a broken motor.
我们去借钱吧
Let's take out a loan.
然后用什么还
And pay it back with what?
当然是把船租出去然后用租金还啊
We hire it out 'til we pay the loan back, obviously.
告诉你一个不幸的消息
Unfortunately for you,
二十一岁之前 你的财产都由我来管
I'm in charge of your finances until you turn 21,
而我不太愿意替你去
and I'm not comfortable takin' out enormous loans
借那么一大笔钱
on your behalf.
乐队还有训练
I have band practice.
能不能先送我回去拿点东西
Can you drive me home to get my stuff
然后再把我送到桑迪家
then drive me over to Sandy's house?
可以啊
Sure.
你为什么不去学个驾照呢 我又不是你的司机
Why don't you take a drivers' s course? I'm not your chauffeur.
因为我答应爸爸十七岁之前不开车
'Cause dad made me promise not to drive 'til I was 17.
行吧 那就这么着吧
Okay, we'll stick with that then.
你想留下来吃晚餐吗
Do you wanna stay for dinner?
我觉得桑迪的妈妈挺喜欢你的
I think Sandy's mother likes you.
她才不喜欢我
No, she doesn't.
我正好知道她喜欢你呢
I happen to know that she does.
这对我们俩都是好事
This could be good for both of us.
还是算了吧
I'd really rather not.
你好歹留下来跟她聊聊天
Well, can you at least just like hang out with her
半小时就行 那样她就不会每隔二十秒就来敲一次门了
for half an hour so I can be alone with Sandy
我和桑迪也能独处一会儿
without her mother knockin' on the door every twenty seconds?
哥们 行不行啊
Come on, man.
你跟她聊聊天有什么难的
All you gotta do is talk to her.
你就不能帮我这个小忙吗
Why can't you help me out a little bit for once
不要只会拖我去见律师
instead of draggin' me to the lawyers
或者去殡仪馆 太平间
and the funeral parlor and the morgue?
不管怎么说 她人很好啊
Anyway, she's really nice.
停停停
Stop, stop, stop, stop. Stop, stop.
- 奥托      - 怎么了 我又慢了?
- Otto...        - What, I'm too slow?
太快了 哥们儿 你一直拖着我们走
Too fast man. You're dragging.
你快太多了
You're way too fast, man.
我又快了啊
I'm too fast.
兄弟 你他妈都快到天上去了
Dude, you're like pulling out of the fucking station ahead of me.
你们这些人少说两句不行吗
Oh my god, you guys, leave him alone.
你到底有没有认真对待乐队的事情
Dude, like, are you serious about this band, or what?
行了 行了
Okay, all right, all right.
- 把他开除吧      - 别来烦我
- Just lay off him.        - Get off my back.
好吧 我们都冷静冷静
All right, everybody just chill here.
再来一遍吧
Let's just, um... Let's just go again.
我们是 响彻云霄
We are stentorian.
帕特里克是我最喜欢的人之一了
Patrick is one of my favorite people.
那挺好的
That's good.
你们在楼上怎么样呀
How's it goin' up there, you guys?
挺好的 谢啦
It's going... It's going fine, thanks!
但我们现在正忙着呢
But we're right in the middle of something.
我们正在专心研究这些复合分数呢
We're just banging out those compound fractions.
好歹我们还知道他们在哪 对吧
At least we know where they are, right?
这倒是真的
That's true.
你要拆几个
How many of those you generally gotta go through
才能挑出一个能用的
before you pick a winner?
我就是想看看要是老有人打扰你
I'd like to see you use one of these goddamn things
你还行不行
with all these interruptions.
操
Oh, fuck me!
怎么了 你没事吧
What happened? Are you ok?
我被你的傻逼娃娃屋给绊倒了
I tripped over your fuckin' doll house.
天呐 你把它弄坏了吗
Oh my god, did you break it?
我不知道 顺便告诉你我没事
I don't know. I'm fine though, by the way.
天呐
Oh my god.
我五岁的时候外婆就把这个娃娃屋给我了
My grandmother gave me that when I was five years old.
这就是她小的时候
It was literally her doll house
她的那个娃娃屋
from when she was a little girl.
那你干嘛把它放在地上啊
Then what's it doin' on the fuckin' floor?
娃娃屋就是放在地上的啊 不然怎么玩
Um, it's a doll house, that's where you play with it!
孩子们 你们怎么了
Kids, what is going on up there?
没事 帕特里克被外婆的娃娃屋给绊倒了
Nothing! Patrick just stubbed his toe on mummer's doll house,
不过没事了
but it's okay!
桑迪 那可是我妈妈的娃娃屋
Sandy, that doll house belonged to my mother.
- 我知道 妈妈      - 如果你要把它砸碎的话
- Yes I know, mom.        - If you're gonna smash it to pieces...
这玩意儿还好好的呢 一点没坏
Nobody is smashin' it to pieces! It's fine!
别担心 吉尔 反正我没事 我的脚趾头也没事
Don't worry, Jill, I'm okay. My toe's gonna be okay.
你到底还想不想操我了
Do you want to fuck me or not?
想啊
Yes.
李 你还想再喝点啤酒吗
Could I get you another beer, Lee?
不用了 谢谢
I'm good. Thank you.
我先失陪一下 就一会儿
Would you excuse me, Lee, one sec?
当然
Sure.
- 戴上了吗      - 是的 简直奇迹
- Is it on?        - Yes. It's a miracle.
来吧 抓紧时间
Okay, hurry up.
稍等一下下
Ow... One second please!
给我起开
Get outta my way!
不好意思
I'm sorry.
怎么了
What's up?
我真是太抱歉了 我知道你们在用功
I'm really sorry, i know you're trying to work,
但我在楼下真是一秒钟都坐不下去了
but I can't sit down there much longer.
怎么了 出什么事吗
Why? What's the problem?
他就是不说话
He won't talk.
我已经没话找话半小时了
I've been trying to make conversation for half an hour.
- 真的吗      - 怎么了
- Are you serious?        - What's the matter?
我知道我不是世界上
I realize I'm not the most fascinating
- 最有魅力的人      - 妈 你说什么呢
- person in the world--        - oh, mom!
但这样子也太过分了
But it's very, very strained.
- 发生了什么      - 你叔叔就是不肯开口说话
- What's going on?        - She can't get your uncle to talk.
他喜欢体育
He likes sports.
打扰到你们我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry to bust things up,
但是我还是想问问你们大概还要多久
but how much longer do you think you're gonna be?
要不你开一下电视看看有没有体育节目
Could you maybe turn on a game?
- 真对不起      - 闭嘴吧你
- I'm sorry.        - Shut up.
妈妈 你别这样
Mummy, please.
你真是帮了我的大忙
You were a tremendous help.
又不是我自己想坐在那的
I didn't ask to sit down there.
你就不能像其他大人一样随便闲聊两句吗
You can't make small talk like every other grown-up in the world?
- 不行      - 你就不能随便扯点什么瞎话打发掉半小时吗
- No.        - You can't talk about boring bullshit for half an hour?
- 不行      - 嘿 现在银行的利率怎么样
- No.        - Hey, how about those interest rates?
- 不行      - 嘿 我上次把我的3A卡给弄丢了
- No, I can't.        - Hey, I lost my triple a card.
- 不行      - 就像所有正常人一样?
- Nope.        - Like everybody else?
不行 不好意思
Nope, sorry.
你真是个混蛋
You're a fucking asshole.
你说她住在哪来着
Where'd you say she lives?
因为这块连房子的影子都没有
'Cause there's, like, no houses here. None.
她是睡在睡袋里吗
What, does she live in a fucking sleeping bag?
鸽子山街119号
119 Pigeon hill street.
鸽子山街 还是鸽子山路?
Pigeon hill street, or Pigeon hill road?
- 鸽子山街      - 好 所以是街
- Pigeon hill street        - Okay, Pigeon hill street.
- 还是鸽子山区      - 街
- Pigeon hill court.        - Street.
- 鸽子山路      - 街
- Pigeon hill road.        - Street.
- 街 知道了      - 我们要去鸽子山街
- Fine, Pigeon hill--        - Pigeon hill street.
- 这是鸽子山路      - 好
- This is pigeon hill road.        - Okay.
- 你是没有导航吗      - 没有 你没看见我正盯着手机上的动画看吗
- You have no GPS whatsoever?        - No, I have a little fucking cartoon.
- 所以你是需要我帮你吗      - 不用了
- You want me to punch it in for you?        - No, I don't.
我搞定了 谢了
I've got it, thank you.
听着
Okay, listen.
你现在是不是很紧张
Are you nervous?
紧张啊
Yeah, I'm nervous.
你真是太聪明了 这都知道
What are you, a fuckin' genius?
算了
Okay, skip it.
我只是想说如果气氛很尴尬就给我发短信
Just want you to text me if anything gets weird.
好 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
老天啊 这真的是我的帕特里克吗
Oh my gosh. Is that my Patrick?
你好 妈妈
Hi, mom.
我太高兴了
I'm so happy.
进来吧 欢迎来我家
Come in. Welcome to my home.
帕特里克 这是我家那位
Patrick. This is my fella.
杰弗里 这是帕特里克
Jeffrey, this is Patrick...
终于见到你了 帕特里克
Great to finally meet you, Patrick.
- 见到你很高兴      - 是啊
- Nice to meet you.        - Yeah.
这是李
And this is Lee.
你好 欢迎
Hey, welcome.
- 谢谢      - 我叫杰弗里
- Thanks.        - Jeffrey.
我是李
Lee.
李 你确定你真的没法留下来吃午餐吗
Now, Lee, are you sure you can't stay for lunch?
我确定
I'm positive. Yeah.
好吧
All right.
来吧
Come, come.
你们真的不用我帮忙吗
Oh, are you sure-- i can't help you--
不用 谢谢 亲爱的
no thanks, honey.
你好好休息就是了
Your job is to relax.
休息就是你的头号任务 听见了吗
That is your number one assignment, okay?
好 那我就不客气了
Okay, all right. I'm really gonna apply myself.
不 我只是开个玩笑而已
No, I was just joking.
我知道 我也开玩笑呢
I know you were. So was I.
你们俩相处的怎么样
How we gettin' along?
- 非常好      - 很好
- Great.        - Great.
你不用这么礼貌的 知道吗
You don't have to be so polite, you know.
我没有很礼貌啊
I'm not being polite.
吃饭前你要不要先洗个手
Did you wanna wash your hands before we eat?
好
Yes.
让我们感激上帝所赐予的食物
For what we are about to receive, let us give thanks.
- 阿门      - 阿门
- Amen.        - Amen.
阿门
Amen.
你可以说阿门 帕特里克
You can say "amen", Patrick.
不会有人强迫你信教
Nobody's tryin' to recruit you.
我说了
I did say "amen".
是吗 好吧
Oh, you did? Okay.
其实你也可以不说
Well, you don't have to.
我知道 我只是很小声地说了一下
Yeah, I know. I just said it really quietly.
没关系的 宝贝
Oh. It's fine, honey.
我知道 看到我你一定觉得很震惊
Look, I know I'm gonna be a shock to you.
毕竟不只是变了一丁点
In a lot of ways.
但我希望那是好的震惊
I'm hoping it's a good shock.
当然了
Yeah.
你还要点什么吗 帕特里克
You need anything else, Patrick?
但愿这些菜还合你胃口
I hope everything's okay.
当然了 都很好吃
Oh yeah, everything's great.
你不用这么拘束
You don't have to be so formal.
我没有啊
I'm not.
我觉得你妈妈只是想
I think your mother wants you to feel--
我只是想让你知道这也是你的家
I'm just sayin' that this is your home, too.
我希望这里也能成为你的家
I want it to be.
我知道
And I know...
I know, uh...
事情对你来说都变了
Things are different for you.
但是 我也不知道怎么说了
Anyway, I don't know.
没关系的
That's okay.
你在学校都学些什么呢 帕特里克
What are you studying at school, Patrick?
就那些东西啊
Oh, well, the usual stuff.
这样吧 我去去就来
You know what? I'm gonna be right back.
你们谁需要我从厨房带什么吗
Does anybody need anything from the kitchen?
- 不用了 谢谢      - 什么都不需要
- No, thanks. Thank you.        - I'm good, no.
你尝了这个青豆没
Did you get some string beans?
还没呢 谢谢
Oh, no, not yet. Thank you.
我...
Let me, um...
我去看下她在里面做什么
Let me just see what she's doin' in there.
她看起来怎么样
So what was she like?
我不知道 她挺紧张的
I don't know. She was pretty nervous.
是吗
Yeah?
那个男的什么样
What was that guy like?
十足的基督徒
He was very Christian.
你知道我们也是基督徒吧
You know, we're Christian, too, right?
我知道
Yes, I know that.
你知道所有的天主教徒都是基督教吧
You are aware that Catholics are Christians?
是的 我知道
Yes, I am aware of that.
不管怎么样 听你这么说她应该是好多了
Well, it sounds like she's doin' better, anyway.
不酗酒了
She's not drinkin'.
也不在精神病院了
She's not in the psych ward.
哇哦
Wow.
你哇什么
Wow, what?
你真是不顾一切想要甩掉我
You'll do anything to get rid of me.
- 你说什么      - 你听到我说什么了
- What?        - You heard me.
胡说八道
That's not true.
亲爱的帕特里克 我写信来是为了感谢你今天能来
Dear Patrick, I'm writing to thank you for today.
你的到来对于你母亲来说意义重大
Your visit meant the world to your mom.
你愿意重新回到她的生活
We are both deeply grateful for the love and trust
所表现出的爱与信任让我们十分感激
you've shown by offering to rejoin her life,
但我觉得你似乎不应该匆忙地将她
but I feel it would be unfair to your mom to rush her along
赶上这条漫长而艰难的道路
the long and challenging road ahead,
所以我希望你可以给我回信
and so I'm going to ask you to write to me
以安排日后的见面
in future to arrange any further visits.
我希望这封信不会打扰…
I hope you won't take this as an intrusion--
你的朋友们今晚在哪呢
where are your friends tonight?
我不知道
I don't know.
为什么不打给那个叫桑迪的姑娘呢
Why don't you call that girl Sandy,
- 看她会不会过来      - 不用了谢谢
- see if she'll come over?        - No, thanks.
不过做得不错
Nice try, though.
你想要对谁开枪 你还是我
Who are you going to shoot, you or me?
你知道这些枪值多少钱吗
Do you know what these things are worth?
不知道
No.
我想把它们卖了
Want to try and sell them
这样就可以给船换个新马达了
so you can have a motor for the boat?
还真是个好主意
That's a really good idea.
太棒了
This is awesome.
是很不错
你想开吗
Do you want to drive?
好啊
Sure.
来吧
All right.
天啊
Oh! Oh, my god!
- 抱歉      - 没事 没事
- I'm so sorry.        - That's all right.
没事 稳一下方向
That's all right. Just straighten her out.
- 天啊      - 稳一下方向
- Oh, my god.        - Straighten her out.
- 没事      - 真是抱歉
- That's okay.        - Sorry.
我去买点东西
Hey, I got to run some chores.
过几个小时回来
I'll be back in a couple hours.
- 你们要带点什么吗      - 不用 谢谢
- You want anything?        - No, thank you.
不用了 谢谢 钱德勒先生
No, thanks, Mr. Chandler.
谢谢
Thank you.
都是陷阱
Set-up city.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
希尔薇·米根还好吗
Oh, yeah? How's Sylvie Mcgann?
谁
Who?
开门吧
Just open the door.
我不觉得这是我们的责任 但是...
I didn't think it was our responsibility, but--
是啊 我的意思是 他们应该...
Yeah, I guess. I mean, they could have--
没事
it's okay.
李
Lee.
嗨
Hi.
蕾切尔 这是李
Rachel, this is Lee.
- 你好      - 李 蕾切尔
- Hello.        - Lee, this is Rachel.
你好 你好
Hi. Hi.
这是迪伦
And this is Dylan.
你不太看得到他
Uh, you can't see him too good.
你好 迪伦
Hi, Dylan.
是个帅小伙
Very handsome.
兰迪 我去开车 然后过来接你吧
Randi, you want me to get the car and pick you up?
- 好      - 不用 我得走了
- Yeah.        - That's okay. I got to go.
那个...我们能...
Actually, could-- could we, uh,
我们能聊两句吗
could we talk for a second?
- 当然      - 好
- Sure.        - Okay.
我去把车开过来 几分钟就好
I'll just pull around. Just be a few minutes.
- 好 谢谢      - 很高兴认识你
- Okay. Thanks.        - Nice to meet you.
- 我也是      - 我马上就回来
- Yeah. You, too.        - Be right back.
我也没什么重要的事要说
I don't have anything big to say.
没事
That's okay.
只是...
I just--
我知道你来这里了 我想...
I know you've been around, and i--
我只是来把帕特里克安顿好
I've just been getting Patrick settled in.
他看起来似乎还不错
It seems like he's doing pretty good, huh?
毕竟出了这种事
Considering.
我想他应该还不错
I think he is, yeah.
我猜你还不知道
I guess you don't know this,
不过我...
but I, uh...
其实我和乔一直有联系
I really kept in touch with Joe.
- 不 我知道的      - 见不到帕特里克
- No, I knew that.        - It's been kind of weird
我还有点不习惯 噢 好吧
for me not seeing Patrick. Oh. Oh, okay.
我不知道
I-- I didn't know.
你可以见他 如果你想见的话
Uh, you could see him if you want.
我们可以一起吃个午饭吗
Could we ever have lunch?
你是说我们 你和我吗
You mean us, you and me?
是的
Yeah.
因为我
Because I, uh...
我对你说了很多很过分的话
I said a lot of terrible things to you.
没事
No.
但是我
But i--
我知道你再也不
I know you never--
可能不想再和我说话了
maybe you don't want to talk to me.
- 不是那样的      - 让我说完
- It's not that.        - Let me finish.
但是
However--
我的心碎了
my heart was broken.
永远都不会好了
It's always going to be broken.
我知道你的心也碎了
And I know yours is broken, too.
但我不用带着...
But I don't have to carry--
我说的那些话
I said things that--
我对你说的那些话简直太该死了
I should fucking burn in hell for what I said to you.
别这样
No. No.
- 真的是太...      - 不 不 不 不
- It was--        - no, no, no, no.
不 兰迪
Randi, no.
对不起
I'm just sorry.
这 我 我不能
It-- i-- I can't ex-- i can't--
我爱你
I love you.
我可能不该这么对你说
Maybe I shouldn't say that.
没事的
No, you can say that.
只是
It's just--
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry. I've got to go.
我们不能一起吃午饭吗
We couldn't have lunch?
真的很抱歉 还是不了吧
I'm really sorry. I don't think so.
谢谢你告诉我这些
I thank you for saying everything you said.
你不能就这样死去
You can't just die.
我没有 我不会
I'm not. I'm not. I'm not.
亲爱的
But, honey-- honey--
我希望你能快乐
and i-- i want you to be happy.
亲爱的 我看到你在附近
Honey, I see you walking around here,
我只是想告诉你
and I just want to tell you--
我想和你说话 兰迪
I would want to talk to you, randi,
- 但是 李      - 拜托 我 我
- but, Lee--        - Please, i-- i-- i--
因为 我
because-- i--
- 李...      - 我
- Lee--        - um, I'm--
- 我试图      - 李 你要
- I'm trying to--        - Lee, you've got to--
我不知道
I don't know what--
这并不是
look, this is not--
我不想折磨你
I don't want to torture you.
你没有折磨我
You're not torturing me.
我只是想告诉你
I just want to tell you
我错了
that I was wrong.
不 不
No. No.
你不明白 我什么都...
You don't understand. There's nothing--
我什么都不在乎了
there's nothing there.
- 什么都不在乎了      - 不是这样的
- There's nothing there.        - That's not true.
- 那不是真的       - 让我说
- That's not true.        - Let me say this.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我明白
I understand you.
我不知道该
I don't know what to--
我知道你明白
I know you understand me.
我...我得走了
I-- i-- I've got to go.
- 不要      - 对不起
- Don't.        - I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 抱歉      - 没事
- Pardon me.        - It's all right.
操
Shit.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
你想打我们 你想打我们?
You want to hit us? Want to hit us?
- 操你妈的      - 来啊 你们这帮混蛋
- God damn it!        - Come on, you little bastard!
小心 小心 小心
Look out, look out, look out.
Look out, look out, look out!
别打了 别打了
Break it up! Break it up!
- 乔治      - 别打了
- George!        - Break it up!
放开他 别打了
Get off him! Break it up!
退后 乔治
Back off, George!
- 操他妈的      - 乔治 你出去
- Fuck him!        - George, get out of here!
- 别打了      - 乔治
- Break him up!        - George!
乔治 把他赶出去
Get him out of here, George!
这是乔∙钱德勒的弟弟
He's Joey Chandler's brother.
- 退后 退后      - 该死的
- Back off, back off.        - Fucking dude--
- 操      - 喂 冷静点
- oh, fuck--        - hey, settle down.
操他妈的 操他妈的
Fuck him! Fuck him!
- 他就是个该死的蠢货      - 冷静点
- He's a fucking douche bag!        - Settle down.
冷静点 你赢了 好吗
Settle down. You won, all right?
去你妈的
Fuck that motherfucker.
- 冷静点      - 好了 哥们
- Settle down.        - Okay, brother.
- 行了吗      - 你赢了 好吗
- You good?        - You won, all right?
- 行了吗      - 操他妈的
- Are we cool?        - Fuck him.
操他妈的
Fuck him!
过来 放开
Come here. Get off.
- 放开 放开      - 放开他
- Get off. Get off.        - Leave him--
- 操你妈的      - 快他妈放开 放开他
- fuck you!        - Get the fuck off. Get him--
要送他去医院吗
Should he go to the hospital?
不用 只是皮外伤
I don't think so. Nothing's broken.
他们用什么打的他
What did they fucking hit him with,
棒球棍吗
a baseball bat?
他们都说是他先动的手
They all just said he started swinging.
帕特里克在哪里
Where's Patrick?
他和孩子们在一起
He's with the kids.
我让他们去买汉堡了
I sent them out for burgers.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
- 李 坐下      - 坐好
- Lee, sit down.        - Sit down.
坐好 没事的
Sit down. It's all right.
我把钱给你
Let me give you some money.
李 别这样 我都付了
Lee, please, I got it.
- 我把钱给你      - 就这样
- I'll give you some money.        - Put that away.
- 拜托 别这样 我付了      - 把钱收起来
- Please, no. I got it.        - Put your money away.
我付了 算我的
I got it. It's on me.
我煮了点咖啡 喝点吧
I made you some coffee. Come on. Drink this.
- 别这样      - 别这样
- Come on.        - Come on.
别这样 伙计
Come on, buddy.
喝一点吧
Just have a little.
没事 我去给你拿点冰块敷脸 好吗
It's all right. I'm going to get you some ice for your face, okay?
没事
It's all right.
有什么要我帮忙的吗 李叔叔
Can I get you anything, uncle Lee?
不用 谢谢 伙计
Oh, no, thanks, buddy.
好吧 那我去睡觉了
All right. I'm going to go to bed.
- 晚安       - 晚安
- Good night.        - Good night.
爸爸
Daddy.
怎么了 亲爱的
Yes, honey?
难道你没发现 我们烧起来了吗
Can't you see we're burning?
不 亲爱的 没有
No, honey. You're not burning.
着火了 着火了
Fire. Fire.
李叔叔 这是什么怪味
Uncle Lee, what-- what is that smell?
我把酱汁烧糊了 没事
I just burned the sauce. Everything's okay.
我在波士顿找了份工作 七月开始上班
I got a job in Boston. Starts in July.
做什么
What is it?
保管员 修理工
Custodian, handyman.
但这次只用跑两栋楼
But it's just two buildings this time, so...
那你在波士顿给我们
And what, uh, delightful Boston neighborhood
挑了什么好小区了吗
have you selected for us to live in?
- 没有      - 什么意思
- None.        - What do you mean?
你不用去波士顿
You don't have to move to Boston.
我会去查尔斯镇
I want to be in Charlestown,
乔治会照顾你的
and George is going to take you.
什么
What?
我上周和他谈了谈
I talked to him last week
解释了现在的情况
and explained the situation to him.
小乔治今年秋天就要去波士顿大学上学了
Georgie junior's going to BU in the fall,
吉米明年就毕业
and Jimmy graduates next year.
在你十八岁之前 我们可以把这房子租出去
We can rent this house out until you turn 18.
十八岁之后你想住的话可以住回来
Then you come back and stay if you want.
等你二十一岁了 你就可以卖了它
When you turn 21, you're allowed to sell it
或者留着 随你的便
or keep it or whatever you want to do.
等夏天过去了 肯定要把船租出去
We definitely have to hire out the boat when summer's over.
就像我们之前说过的那样
Just like we talked about.
等你拿到执照
When you get your license,
我们到时候再决定怎么办
then we can-- we can just figure that out when it happens.
我还是托管人
I'm still the trustee.
但乔托付给我的财产方面的东西
But all the financial stuff that Joe set up for me
都会转到乔治那里
is going to get transferred over to George.
所以除了你不用搬家之外
So basically everything's staying the same,
一切照旧
except you don't have to move.
谢谢 但是 谁...
Thank you, but, like, who's--
他们就成了我的监护人了吗
are they going to be my guardians, or are you going--
他们会收养你
they're going to adopt you.
总之 我目前是这么打算的
Anyway, that's just how I set it up.
不过也不是一定要这样 你说了算
You don't have to. It's up to you.
所以你就要这样消失了吗
So you're just going to disappear?
不
No.
我帮你打点好了一切 这样你就可以留在这里
I set it up this way so you could stay here.
他们也很高兴能收养你
And they're really glad to have you.
- 他们...      - 我知道 我知道
- They--        - I know, I know.
他们很好
I mean, they're great, but...
但为什么你不能留下
Why can't you stay?
别这样 小帕
Come on, Patty.
我走不出来
I can't beat it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
会没事的
It's going to be okay.
你是斯坦·钱德勒的儿子吗
Are you one of Stan Chandler's boys?
是的 我叫李
Yeah. I'm Lee.
很久以前 我常和你父亲下西洋棋
I used to play chess with your father a long time ago.
他很厉害
He was a excellent chess player.
是的
That's him.
他去世了 是吗
He's not still living, is he?
是的
No.
我听闻
One of the sons
最近他的一个儿子也去世了
passed away recently, I heard.
是的 就是我哥 乔
Uh, yeah, my brother Joe.
他是个很不错的人
Very personable man.
是的
Yeah.
我父亲是在1959年去世的
My father passed away in 1959.
当时还很年轻
A young man.
在一搜捕捞金枪鱼的船上工作
He worked on a tuna boat.
有一天早上他出海了
He got up one morning.
寻常天气 一点都不恶劣
Same weather, nothing dramatic.
但他再也没回来
And he never returned.
没有信号 没有呼救
No signals, no maydays.
也没人知道到底发生了什么
No one ever found out what happened to him.
我去买点冰激凌
I'm going to get some ice cream.
去吧
Go ahead.
能给我点钱吗
Can I have some money?
嗯
Yes.
我什么时候搬去和乔治住
So when am I supposed to move in with Georgie?
七月
July.
我现在都还没有找到房子
I don't even have a place to live yet.
他们没有给你安排公寓吗
They don't give you an apartment?
有 但我想要有两个房间的公寓
Yeah, but I'm looking for one with an extra room.
能放下一张沙发
A room for a pull-out sofa or--
为什么
what for?
万一你什么时候想来看我呢
So you can come visit some time.
或者你想来波士顿参观参观大学
Or if you want to look at colleges in Boston,
到时候你就能住我那里
you could stay overnight.
我不会去读大学的
I'm not going to college.
行吧 那我用那个房间来堆我的杂物
All right, then I'll have an extra room for all my shit.
我们非得现在谈这个吗
Do we have to talk about this now?
不
No.
扔得好
Great throw.
别管它了
Just let it go.
注意了
Heads up.
奇遇电影字幕组
QY-174
翻译：@阿囤小兄弟 @一只醉丁 @不见老阿
@movie404 @鱼饲料1 @Tien_Sun
时间轴：@Edandelion_ @一只醉丁 @33-eR
@-GOOEY @没什么能难倒LeoQ
校对：@一个Delpy  @Florrie_likkke
特效：@一只醉丁
更多资讯请关注官方公众号：cinematik